<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Login</string>
    <string name="already_have_an_account">Already Have an Account?</string>

    <string name="facebook_app_id">1201461980678308</string>
    <string name="fb_login_protocol_scheme">fb1234</string>
    <string name="facebook_client_token">56789</string>
    <string name="title_activity_agrimap">Agrimap</string>


    <string name="Date_info"><b>1. Introduction</b>\n\nDate palm is oldest tree cultivated on earth. They are excellent source of calcium, sugar, iron and potassium. They are used in many social and religious festivals. Also they have many health benefits like relive constipation, reduce heart disease, control diarrhea and help in pregnancy. It is also used for making different products such as Chutney, pickles, jam, juice and other bakery items.\n\nDate cultivation is mainly concentrated in Arabic countries, Israel and Africa. Iran is major producer and exporter of dates. From last decades Indian Government take lot of effort and increased area under date palm cultivation. In India, Rajasthan,Gujarat, Tamil Nadu and Keraa are major date growing states.\n\n\n<b>2. Climate</b>\n\nDates require low relative humidity and plenty of sunshine for their best growth.It requires long days with plenty of sunshine, night temperatures and winter days without frost.
It does not prefer rain especially at the time of flowering and fruit setting.\n\n\n<b>3. Soil</b>\n\nDates require well drained deep sandy loam soils with pH of 8.0 to 10.0.The soil should have ability to hold the moisture.\nThe dates also can be grown in saline and alkaline soils with lower yield. The soil should be free from calcium carbonateand should not have any hard pan at least up to 2.5 meter for better root development.\n\n\n<b>4. Fertilizers</b>\n\n In september to October month, application of FYMI0 to 15 kg to young plants and 30 to 40 kg per tree to mature plant is done.\nUrea @ 44 kg is appled on one year plant to mature tree.Application of urea is done in two equal splits,First dose is given before flowering and the remaining half dose is given after fruit set is done in April.\nAlong with recommended fertilizer use Criyagen DNP 25g/pit as basal dose/acre. Foliar spray Criyagen zyme - 3ml/ liter + All 19 bgm/liter for plant development t ist - 20 days after planting, 2nd- 15 days after 1st spray) Foliar Spray Bio-maxx @ 3ml/ liter once before b0% of tlowering and once after b0% pod formation.\n\n\n<b>5. Harvesting</b>\n\nFour to five year after plantation, date palm tree are ready for first harvest. Fruits are harvested at three stages, Khalal or doka stage (fresh fruits), soft or ripen stage (pind or tamar) and dry stage (chuhhara). Complete harvesting before start of monsoon season.
</string>

    <string name="coc_info"><b>1. Introduction</b>\n\nThe coconut palm is referred to as Kalpavriksha -the tree of heaven as each and every part of the palm is useful to mankind in one way or other. It provides food, drink, fuel and timber. Millions of farnilies in India depend on coconut fortheir livelihood either directly or indirectly India ranks third in area and production of coconut in the world.\nThe four southern states viz. Karnataka ,Kerala, Tamil Nadu and Andhra Pradesh are the major coconut producing states in India accounting for more than 90 per cent of area and production.\nThere is a great scope for enhancing thee productivity of coconut through adoption of scientific cultivation technologies, which are described here under.\n\n\n<b>3. Soil</b>\n\nRed sandy loam, laterite and alluvial soils are suitable. Select sites with deep (not less than 1.5 m depth) well drained soil heavy, imperfectly drained soil is unsuitable. Avoid shallow soils with underlying hard rock, low to lying areas subject to water stagnation and heavy clayey soils. Soil with a minimum depth of 1.2 m and fairly good water holding capacity is preferred for coconut cultivation. However, in lands, reclaimed by heaping alternate layers of sand and clay. coconut thrives welI. Proper supply of moisture either through well distributed rainfall or irrigation and sufficient drainage are essential for coconut. Coconut can be grown in soil with pH of 5.2 to 8.6\n\n\n<b>4. Method of Planting</b>\n\nBefore planting the pits are filled up with top soil and powdered cow dung/ compost up to a depth of 50 to 60 cm. Then take a small pit inside this, so as to accommodate the nut attached to the seedling. Plant the seedling inside this pit andfill up with soil.Press the soil well so as to avoid water stagnation. If there is chance for white-ant attack apply Sevidol 86 (5gm.) inside the small pit before planting. In laterite areas apply 2 kg common salt per pit for improving the physical condition of the soil.Burying 25 to 30 coconut husks per pit in layers will be useful for moisture conservation.
\n\n\n<b>5. Fertilizers</b>\n\n1. From 5th year onwards, apply 50 kg of FYM or Compost or green manure. 1.3 kg urea (560 g N),2.0 kg super phosphate (320 g P205) and 2.0 k9 muriate of potash (1200 g K20) in two equal splits during June - July and December January. \n2. Apply manures and fertilizers in circular basins of 1.8 m from the base of the palm, incorporate and irrigate. \n3. During 2nd, 3rd and 4th year , % cand 4 doses of the above fertilizer schedule should be Cdopted respectivey. \n4. Sufficient moisture should be preset at the time of manuring. \n5.Fertigation may be done at monthly intervals with 75% of the recommended dose of the above fertilzers. \n6 Phosphorus may be applied as super phosphate in the basins and incorporated. \n\n\n\n<b>6. Weeding</b>\n\nKeep the pits tree of weeds by Periodical weeding. Remove the soil covering the collar of seedlings. As the seedlings grow and form stem, fill up the pits gradually by cutting the sides. Proper intercuitivation provides control of weeds and creates soil mulch. \nAny tilage system \plougning, digging. raking or forming mounds) that provides soil mulch and control weeds may be followed depending upon local conditions. Ihe inter-space in the coconut garden has to be ploughed twice ina year in June - July and December - January tor laterite, sandy and red sandy loam soils give two ploughing or diggings in May-June and September-October and one raking in Janudiy.\n\n\n<b>7. Harvesting</b>\n\nTwelve months old nuts are harvested at the interval of 30-45 days for seed as well as copra making and culinary purposes.For household use keep the nuts in verticca direction.
However, for tender nut purposes 7 to 8 months old nuts are harvested. The nuts can be narvested using coconut climbers.Nuts which are ll months old give niber of good quality. This is suitable for coir fiber in case of tall variety, the nut harvested tor seed purpose can be stored ior 2 to 3 months period before sowing, whereas in case of dwarts and hybrids, nuts should be sown with in a period of 10 -15 days of harvest. On an average, we can have eight harvests, though the coconut palm produces inflorescence every month. \nFor oil extraction, nuts are generally sun dried for copra making. in this case there is a chance odirt accumulation followed by oil quality deterioration, nuts can be dried in various types of driers available {Kiln, electric and solar driers and aiso Sun arying. \nGood quality copra can be obtained in short time by using these driers. Moisture content in copra for final use shoulkd be around 5-6%. Store\n\n\n<b>8. Yield</b>\n\nAverage yield: 80 100 nuts/paim/year depending on the variety.\nDwarf varieties-70 - 80 nuts/palm/year\nTall varieties 80 100 nuts/palm/year\nHybrids -100 - 130 nuts/ palm/year.
Average yield: 80 100 nuts/paim/year depending on the variety. \nDwarf varieties-70 - 80 nuts/palm/year\nTall varieties -80 100 nuts/palm/year\nHybrids -100 - 130 nuts/ palm/year\n
    </string>


    <string name="tea_info"><b> 1. Introduction</b>\n\nTea plantations look like a huge forest made up of small trees that rarely reach above 1.5m in height. When their trunks are thick and gnarled they show that their age is much greater than their small size would suggest. In their natural state tea plants can reach a height of 15 to 20m.\n\n\n<b> 2. Soil</b>\n\nTea requires well drained soil with high amount of organic matter and pH 4.5 to 5.5.\n\n\n<b> 3. Climate</b>\n\nThe performance of tea is excellent at elevations ranging from 1000 to 2500 m.Optimum temperature: 20 270 C.\n\n\n<b> 4. Planting, Seed and Method </b>\n\nSeason and planting May June or September October Sleeves should be opened lengthwise without injuring the roots and planted in the pit and the soil is gently pressed. \nMethods of planting\na. Single Hedge System In this method, the spacing adopted is 120 x 0.75m accommodating 10,800 plants/ha. \nb. Double Hedge System In this method, the spacing adopted is 1.35 x 0.75x 0.75 m accommodating 13,200 plants/ha. \n\n\n\n<b>5. Planting of Cutting</b>\n\nThe sleeves are watered thoroughly and holes are made in the soil. The cuttings are inserted in the hole and the soil around is pressed firmly to avoid airspace followed by watering Small polythene tents may be provided which maintain high humidity andl regulate the temperature inside Cuttings may take 10 12 weeks for rooting. \nAfter 90 days i.e. when all the cuttings have rooted, the polythene tent may be removed gradually over a period of 10 15 days.
\n\n\n<b>6. Fertilizers</b>\n\nManuring should be done 2 months after planting. Phosphorous should be applied at 80 to100 kg/ha as Rock phosphate once in a year by placement at 15 25 cm depth up to the first pruning and thereafter once in two years. N:K ratio 2:3 should be adapted for the first 3 years and a ratio 1: 1 thereafter\n\n\n<b>7. Harvesting</b>\n	Plucking commences when the tea bush is 3 years old. The plucking of extreme tip of the growing branch consists of an unopened bud together with two leaves is popularly known as "Two leaves anda bud', while fine plucking is anythingless than this. In South India plucking continues throughout the year at weekly intervals during March May and at intervals of 10 -14 days during the other months. Rush period During rush period harvesting is done at 7 to 10 days interval. \nLean period\nDuring lean period harvesting is done at 10 15days interval. \n\n\n\n<b>8. Yield</b>\n\nThe yield of green leaves is 10 t/ha
    </string>


    <string name="Arecnut_info"><b>1. Introduction</b>\n\nThe areca nut palm is the source of common chewing nut, popularly known as betel nut or Supari. In India it is extensively used by large sections of people and is very much linked with religious practices. India is the largest producer of areca nut and at the same time largest consumer also .Major states cultivating this cropare Karnataka (40%), Kerala (25%), Assam(20%), Tamil Nadu, Meghalaya and West Bengal.\n\n\n<b> 2. Climate</b>\n\nThe cultivation of are canut is mostly confined to 28° north and south of the equator. It grows well within the temperature range of 14°C and 36°C and is adversely affected by temperatures below 10C and above 40°C. Extremes of temperature and wide diurnal variations are not conducive for the healthy growth of the palms. Are canut can be grown in areas receiving annual rainfall of 750 mm in Maidan parts of Karnataka to 4,500 mm in Malnad areas of Karnataka. In areas where there is prolonged dry spell, the palms are irrigated Due to its susceptibility to low temperature, a good crop of are canut cannot be obtained at an altitude of more than 1000 m MsL. \n\n\n<b> 3. Soil</b>\n\nThe largest area under the crop is found in gravelly laterite soils of red clay type. It can also be grown on fertile clay loam soils. Sticky clay, sandy, alluviail, brackish and calcareous soils are not suitable for are canut cultivation.\n\n\n<b> 4. Sowing and Seed</b>\n\nFor raising seedlings seed nuts from pre to marked and pre to potent mother palms of outstanding performance are selected and sown at a spacing of 5 to 6 cm apart in sand beds under partial shade with their stalk end pointing upwards. After the sprouts have produced two to three leaves, they are transplanted to a polythene bag 30 x 10 cm filled with forest soil and are allowed to grow for 12 to 18 months under partial shade. The seedlings can also be transplanted in secondary nursery beds with a spacing of 30 cm on either side. Periodical watering should be given.\nSeason:\nJune December is found to be the optimum. \n Planting: \nDwarf and compact seedlings with more number of leaves should be selected. Seedlings of 1 to 2\nyears age are planted in pits of about 90 cm x 90 cmx 90 cm at a spacing of 2.75 m either way and covered with soil to the collar level and pressed around. Provide shade during summer months. Growing Banana or other crops in advance may also provide shade.\n\n\n<b> 5. Sowing and Seed Raising of Seedilings:</b>\n\nAre canut is propagated only by seeds. There are four steps in selection and raising of are canut seedlings viz, selection of mother palms, selection of seed nuts, gemindtion and raising the seedlings and selection of seedlings.\nSelection of Mother plant:\nThe criteria for the selection of mother palm are early bearing, regular bearing habit, large number of leaves on the crown, shorter internodes and high fruit set.\nSelection of seed nut:\nFully ripened nuts having weight of above 35 g should be selected. The nuts selected should float vertically with calyx-end pointing upwards when allowed to float on water. These nuts produce the seedlings of gredter vigour.\nselection of seedlings:\n
Tweve to eighteen-month-old seedlings are to be selected and transplainted in the main fied. Seedlings with maximum number of leaves (five or above), minimum height and maximum girth Cire to be selected for planting. The selected seedlings should be removed with a ball of earth.\n\n\n<b>6. Nutrient Requirement</b>\n\nAnnual application of 100 g N (220 g urea). 40 g P205 (200 g rock phosphate) and 140g K20 (235 g muriate of potash) in addition to 12 kg each of green leaf and compost per palm per year is recommended. The fertilizers are to be applied in two split doses. One third of the fertilizer is applied in May June and two third along with the organics during September to October. Fertilizers are applied in basins around the poalm dug to a depth of 15 to 20 cm and 0.5 to 1.0 m radius leaving 20 cm from the base of the palm. After application, the soil is rolled up and covered with organic matter and soil.\n\n\n<b>7. Irrigation and Intercropping</b>\n\n
Areca nut cannot withstand drought tor a long time. Being a perennial crop, once affected by water stress, it may require two-three years to regain the normal vigour and yield. The death of palms due to moisture stress is also not uncommon. Irrigation intervals of 5 and 10 days were found superior throughout the season. The quantity of water to be applied is about 200 lt per palm/ irrigation.\nDuring the summer, majority of the farmers facescarcity of water and it will be difficult to supply the required water to the palms. To overcome this problem, new irrigation methods were tried which can save water without attecting the yield of areca nut. They are sprinklers and drip irigation methods. Sprinkler and dripirigations can save 20 and 44 per cent respectively of water.\n<b>Intercropping</b>Cococ, black pepper, coffee, vanilla, cinnamon,clove and citrus.\n\n\n<b>8. Harvesting and Yield</b>\n\n<b>Harvest</b>\nThe bearing starts after 5 years of planting. Nutsare harvested when they are three quarters ripe.The number of harvests will vary from three tofive in one year depending upon the season andplace of cultivation.\n<b>Yield</b>\nAn average of about 1250 kg/ha can beobtained.
</string>


    <string name="Choki_info"><b>1. Introduction</b>\n\nCocoa is an important commercial plantation crop of the world. Cocoa is a crop of humid tropics and so it was introduced as a mixed crop in India in areas where the environments suit the crop. It is cultivated in coconut and areca nut plantations large scale from 1970 onwards. It is grown as an under- storey intercrop with sufficient shade in southern states of India. InIndia, the current production is about 12,000 Metric Tonnes and Tamil Nadu produces about 400 MetricTonnes.\n\n\n<b>2. Climate</b>\n\nThe natural habitat of the cocoa tree is in the owner storey to the evergreen rainforest, and climatic factors, particularly temperature and rainfall, are important in encouraging optimum growth. Cocoa is a perennial crop, and it can withstand different seasonal variations with good health and yield potential. Cocoa is normally cultivated at altitudes up to 1200 m above MSL with an annual rainfall of 1000 mm to 2000 mm and a relative humidity of 80 2 with maximum 36 degree C and minimum temperature of 15 degree C. \n\n\n<b>3. Soil</b>\n\n
Cocoa can be grown as intercrop in coconut and areca nut gardens. It is predominantly grown on red laterite soils.
It thrives well on wide range of soil types with pH ranging from 4.5- 8.0 with optimum being 6.5-7.0.\n\n\n<b>4. Varieties</b>\n\nThere are three varietal types in cocoa namely Criollo, Forastero and interior. Forastero types are known to perform well under Indian conditions. Kerala Agricultural university has reeled: seed improved clones of Forastero types namely CCRP 1,CCRP 2, cCRP to 3,CCRP 4, CCRP to 5, CCRP 6 and CCRP to 7 and 3 hybrids CCRP 8, CCRP to 9, CCRP to 10.Central. Plantation Crops Research Institute, Vital has released one clone named as VTLCC to l and 4 hybrids namely VTLCHI, VTLCH2, VTLCH3 andVTLCH Based on survey made during 2008 to 2012 in Tamandu, totally 1bl trees were identified for yield and quality. These trees were continuously evaluated and best performing ten elite trees were selected and named as TNAUcCl to TNAUCCIO.The clonal propagation of these trees are in Progress. \n\n\n<b>5. Harvesting and Processing</b>\n\nCoco produces towers from the šrd year of planting onwards and economic yield starts from 5 th year. Properly well maintained (irrigation per nutrient management) tree yielded 1 to 2 kg of pods per tree per year .Pods take about l40 t0 16u days to ripen. Generally, cocoa gives two main crops in a year, ie. September to January and June to August. offseason crops may be seen throughout the year especially under irrigated condition.The stage of maturity of the pod is best judged by change of color of pods. Pods that are green when immature turn yellow when mature and reddish pods turn yellow or orange.The change in color starts from the grooves on the pods and then spreads to the entire surface.\n\n\n<b>7. Fertilizer schedule for cocoa </b>\n\n<b>Method of application:</b>\nFertilizer may be applied uniformly around the base of the tree up to a radius of 30 cm during the first year, forked and incorporated into the Oll .For grown up plants the best method is to rake and mix the fertilizers with soil in shallow basinsof around 75 cm. This radius may be increased gradually up to 150 cm after third year. Care should be taken not to spill the inorganic fertilizers on the trunk, Drenches or leaves or young trees in order to avoid burning<b>brip (Fertigation): </b>\nFertilizers Can be applied through drip irrigation system (fertigation). Weighed quantity of fertilizers as per schedule was dissolved in water and then injected to Sub-main through venturi and then to lateral lines as per treatment. Drip irrigation is done once in 2 days. The fertilizers are applied through dip irrigation at weekly intervals. 100:40140 kg of N, P and K areapplied through drip and fertigation in different stages of crop growth as detailed below. Water soluble fertilizersAll 19(19% N: 19 % P: 19 % K), Mono – Ammonium Phosphate (MAP 12:61:00 % NPK), Proprietary water soluble form of N and fertilizers containing 13% N and 45 %K (multi k) and Urea (46% N). 100 % RDF as wsF through fertigation by drip irrigation recorded more pod weight (486.82 g), number of pods tree-1(56.87) Pulp + bean weight pod-1 (148.79 g), number of earns per pod (48.62), single bean fresh weight (3.10g), single bean dry weight (1.24 g) and dry weight of the beans per tree (3.429g).
    </string>


    <string name="Rubber_info"><b>1. Introduction</b>\n\nRubber is an important commercial agricultural product, collected from the latex of the tree Hevea Brasiliense’s. It is an indigenous tree of tropical rainforest of Amazon basin of Brazil. Rubber is useful because of its invaluable qualities such as elasticity, resistance to water and non-conduction of electricity. Rubber cultivation had its beginnings in 1876, when Sir Henry Wickham brought Hevea seeds to Kew Gardens in London where he succeeded in germinating trees which he sent to Sri Lanka. Following this experiment, numerous plantations begun in the British and Malay Archipelago, the regions which long supplied most of the worlds natural rubber.\n\n\n<b>2. Soil</b>\n\n
It requires deep and Lateritic fertile soil with an acidic pH of 4.5 to 6.0 and highly deficient in available phosphor
\n\n\n<b>3. Climate</b>\n\nTropical climate with annual rainfall of 2000 4500 mm is suited for cultivation. Minimum and maximum temperature should be ranged from 25 to 34°C with 80 % relative humidity is ideal for cultivation. Regions prone to heavy winds should be avoidecd. \n\n\n<b>4. Planting</b>\n\n<b>Season: </b>\n June July is optimum for cultivation Method of propagation: Propagated by green budding, brown budding and crown budding.<b>Nursery: </b>\n
Bed size 60-120 cm width and of convenient length. Spacing: Seedling stumps 23 x 23 cm, 30 x 30 cm and 34 x 20 cm
Budded stumps 30 x 30 cm Stump budding 60 x 60 cmbBud wood nursery - 60 x 90 cm or 60x 120 cm. \n\n\n<b>5. Manuring</b>\n\n Basal-2.5 t/ha of FYM and 350kg/ha of Rock Phosphate. 1.5 2 months after planting -10:10:4:1.5 NPKMg mixture -2500 kg/ha. Urea 550 kg /ha -3 to 3.5 months. <b>Planting: </b>\n Pit size of 1 m3 are dug and filled up with top soil and compost Spacing for Budded plants Hilly areas 6.7 X 3.4Plains 4.9 x 4.9 Spacing for Seedlings Hilly areas 6.1 X 3.0 Plains 4.6 X 4.6 <b>Insitu sowing: </b>\nGerminated seeds are sown insitu in the pits. Healthy ones are retained and the others removed.\n\n\n<b>6. Fertilizers</b>\n\nFor immature rubber trees at pre-tapping stage, apply 12 kg of compost or FYM and 120 g of rock phosphate in each pit before planting. Apply 10:10:4:1.5 NPK and Mg as per schedule given below in the Table. 1. Apply 400 kg of mixture/ha in 2 doses, once in April/May and another in September/October from the 5th year till the tree is ready for tapping Along with above recommended add DNP and PH-50 to maintain soil micro-biota, their by to get good yield.<b>Matured rubber trees under tapping: </b>\nFor matured rubber trees under tapping apply NPK 10:10:10 grade mixtures at the rate of 900 g tree (300 kg/ha) every year in two split doses. Add 10 kg commercial Magnesium sulphate for every 100 kg of the above mixture if there is magnesium deficiency. \n\n\n<b>7. Intercultural operation</b>\n\n <b>After-cultivation: </b>\nGrowing of cover crops, incorporation of cover crops and weeding are important operations. Pueraria phraseologies, Compendium, Centrosome pubescents monoids and Disodium evalifolium are common cover crops.<b>Ethel treatment: </b>\nEthel is recommended to increase latex yield of trees. It is applied at 5% a.i. concentration with a brush below the tapping cut to a width of 5 cm after light scraping of the outer bark. The first application may be done after a drought period preferably after a few pre-monsoon showers and subsequent applications may be done in September and November.However, continuous application of Ethrel is not recommended for periods of more than 3 years at a stretch.\n\n\n<b>8. Yield</b>\n\nRubber yield steeply increases year by year, reaching a peak after 14 years of planting. In South India, the annual yield of rubber is 150 kg/} ac from seedlings trees, whereas budded plants yield 400 kg/ac.
    </string>


    <string name="Cashew_info"><b>1. Introduction</b>\n\cashew (Anacarclium occidentale L) a native of Eastern Brazil introduced to India just as other commercial crops like Rubber, Coffee, Tea etc. by the Portuguese nearly five centuries back. he nrst introduction of cashew  in did was made in Goa trom where it spread to other parts of the country. In the beginning it was mainly considered ds a crop tor afforestation and soil binder to check erosions. The nuts, apple another by products of this crop are of commercia importance. Though its commercial exploitation began from the early 1960s, marginal lands and denuded forests were the areas set apart for the plan tation development. Due to the absence of high yielding varieties and multiplication techniques, seeds and seedlings were used for plantation development in an unscientific manner. However, as a result of government interventions, coupled with sustained efforts of Research, Development organizations and farmers the development of Cashew Plantations has become re oriented in a scientific manner to great extent Because of Its adaptive debility in wide range ot agro climatic conditions and excellent return per unit area, Cashew has attained the status of anexport oriented crop of high commercial value.\n\n\n<b>2. Climate</b>\n\nIt is a hardy tropical plant and does not exact a very specific, climate. It can come up in places situated within 35 latitude on either side of the equator and also in the hill ranges up to 700 m MSL. It can grow well in places receiving rainfall from 50 cm to 250 cm and tolerate a temperature range of 25 to 49 C. it requires a bright weather and does not tolerate excessive Shade\n\n\n<b> 3. Soil</b>\n\cashew is cultivated on a wide variety of soils in India like laterite, red and coastal sandy soil. To a limited extent, it is also grown on black soils. It can be also grown in hill slopes in virgin organic matter rich soils. They do not prefer water loggedor saline soils.\n\n\n<b>4. Varieties</b>\n\n Since cashew is a highly cross-pollinated crop, planting of seedlings is not recommended now. Various cashew research centres have released improved clones, which are either selections from seedling population or hybrids.  BBPI, BBP2, BBP3, Vengrulal,2,3,4,5,6,7. Vridhachalam,2,3, Ullall,2,3, Chintamani-1, Anakayam-1 etc.\n\n\n<b>5. Planting</b>\n\nJune December is optimum for cultivation. Spacing A spacing of 7 m either way is adopted.High Density Planting spacing of 5 x 4 m accommodating 500 plants per hectare is recommended prune the interlocking branches during the July-August to maintain the frame Requirement of plants About 80 plants/ac can be planted .Propagation Mainly propagated by soft wood grafting. Air layering and epicotyls grafting \n\n\n<b>6. Preparation of field</b>\n\n Pits of 45 cmx 45 cm x 45 cm size are dug and filled up with a mixture of soil + 10 kg FYM one kg neem cake. \n\n\n<b>7. Training and pruning:</b>\n\develop the trunk to a height of 1 m by removing low lying branches. The dried twigs and branches should be removed every year. \n\n\n<b>8.. Plant protection: </b>\n\n<b>1. Grubs bore</b><b>Symptoms: </b>Grubs bore into the bark in their early stages and make excessive tunnels in all directions causing wilting of branches and then the tree as a whole. Roots are also affected. <b>MANAGEMENT</b>\n <b>1. Collection and destruction of affected shoots</b> <b>2. Swabbing the bark</b> \n\n\n<b>9.Harvest</b>\n\n The starts yielding 3rd year onwards. The peak picking months are March to May. Good nuts are grey green, smooth and well filled. After picking, the nuts are separated from the apple and dried in the sun for two to three days to bringdown the moisture content to 10 to 12 %. Properly dried nuts are paced in walkathon bags. This will keep for 6 months.\n\n\n<b>14.Yield</b>\n\nabout 3- 4 kg per tree per year can be obtained.
    </string>

    <string name="Garlic_info"><b>1.Introduction</b>\n\nGarlic, a native of Southern Europe is one of the important bulb crops grown and used as a spice or condiment throughout India. Gujarat followed by Orissa are the largest producing states. It possesses a high natritive value, its preparations are administered as a cure against stomach disease, sore eyes and ear ache. It is commonly used in the preparation of various dishes. Allicin, the principle amoebic dysentry and is also having many other medicinal properties.\n\n\n<b>2.Climate and Soil</b>\n\nIt is grown under a wide range of climatic conditions. However, it cannot stand too hot or too cold weather. It prefers moderate temperature in summer as well as in winter. Short days are very favourable for the formation of bulbs. It can be grown well at elevations of 1000 to 1300 m above MSL. Garlic requires well drained loamy soils, rich in humus, with fairly good content of potash. The crop raised on sandy or loose soil does soils, the bulbs produced are deformed and during harvesting, many bulbs are broken and bruised and so they do not keep well in storage.\n\n\n<b>3.Varieties</b>\n\nThere is no distinct variety of garlic. Local varieties are either white in colour and have fairly big bulbs with a better keeping quality and a higher yield or red in colour with pungency. Tamil Nadu Agricultural University has recently released one improved variety by clonal selection viz., Ooty 1 Garlic. It is a high yielder (17t/ha) with a shorter duration of 120 to 130 days. The bulbs are big sized weighing 20 to 30g and each bulb has 22 to 25 cloves, which are dull white in colour.\n\n\n<b>4.Propagation</b>\n\nGarlic is propagated by cloves. All the cloves are planted except the long slender once in the centre of the bulb. Bulbs with side growth should be discarded. Healthy cloves or bulbils free from disease and injuries should be used for sowing and about 150 to 200 kg cloves are required to plant one hectare. They are sown by dibbling or furrow planting.\n\n\n<b>Dibbling: </b>The field is divided into small plots convenient for irrigation Cloves may be dibbled 5 to 7.5cm deep, keeping their growing ends upwards. They are laced 7.5cm apart from each other in rows of 15cm apart and then they are covered with loose soil. June-July and October-November are the normal planting seasons for garlic.\n<b>Furrow planting:</b> The furrows are made 15 cm with hand how or a cotton drill. In these furrows, cloves are dropped by hand 7.5 to 10 cm apart. They are covered lightly with loose soil and a light irrigation is given.\n\n\n<b>5.Manures and fertilisers</b>\n\nAbout 25 tonnes of farm yard manure is applied as a basal dose along with 60kg Nitrogen and 50 kg in each of Phosphorus and Potash. Forty five days after planting 60kg Nitrogen is applied again as top dressing.\n\n\n<b>6.Irrigation</b>\n\nFirst irrigation is given after sowing and then field is irrigated every 10 to 15 days depending upon the soil moisture availability. There should not be any scarcity of moisture in the growing season, otherwise, the development of the bulbs will be affected. The last irrigation should be given 2 to 3 before harvesting for making it easy without damaging the bulbs. In South India hills, they are mostly grown as a rainfed crop.\n\n\n<b>7.Harvesting</b>\n\nGarlic is a crop of 4 to 5 months duration. When the leaves start turning yellowish or brownish and show signs of drying up, the crop is ready for harvest. The plants are then pulled out or uprooted with a country plough and are tied into small bundles which are then kept in the field or in the shade or 2 to 3 days for curing and drying so that the bulbs become hard and their keeping quality is improved. The bulbs may be stored by hanging them on bamboo sticks or by keeping them on dry sand on the market, the dried stalks are removed and bulbs are cleaned. Well cured garlic bulbs can be kept for 1 to 1 half months in an ordinary well ventilated room. If dust smoke is given to it, the bulbs can be stored for 8 to 10 months. They can also be stored at 320F with 60% R.H. Average yield level is 6 to 8 t per ha.\n\n\n<b>8.Plant protection</b>\n\nThrips cause withering of the leaves. Application of methyl demeton 25EC 1 ml/litre will check the incidence. Leaf spot is the most important disease. Spraying Dithane M-45 at fortnightly intervals at 2.5g in one litre of water is recommended.\n\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="Clove_info"><b>1.SPICES  CONDIMENTS : </b>\n\nClove, the dried unopened flower buds of the evergreen tree, Syzygium aromaticum, (Syn. Eugenia caryophyllus) is an important spices noted for its flavour and medicinal values. It is indigenous to Moluccas island (Indonesia) and was introduced to India around 1800 A.D. by the East Indian Company in their spice garden in Courtallam, Tamil Nadu. The major producers of this spice today are Indonesia, Zanzibar and Madagascar. World production is estimated to be 63,700 tonnes. Indonesia alone accounts for 66 % of the world production. The important clove growing regions in India now are the Nilgiris, Tirunelveli and Kanyakumari districts of Tamil Nadu, Calicut, Kottayam, Quilon and Trivandrum districts of Kerala and South Kanara district of Karnataka.Food processing industry uses both whole and ground form of cloves in various preparations. Clove oil is used in perfumeries, pharmaceuticals and flavouring industries. Clove oleoresin is also increasingly used in the food processing industry. In Indonesia, the major part is absorbed for making KRETEK cigarette industry. The clove is an evergreen tree often reaching a height of 7 to 15 metres. Leaves posses plenty of oil glands on the lower surface.\n\n\n<b>2.Climate and Soil</b>\n\nClove is strictly a tropical plant and requires a warm humid climate having a temperature of 20 to 300C. Humid atmospheric condition and a well distributed annual rainfall of 150 to 250 cm are essential. It thrives well in all situations ranging from sea level up to an altitude of 1500 metres and also in places proximal to and away from sea. Deep black loam soil with high humus content found in the forest region is best suited for clove cultivation. It grows satisfactorily on laterite soils, clay loams and rich black soils having good drainage. Sandy soil is not suitable.\n\n\n<b>3.Propagation</b>\n\nClove is propagated through seed, which is called mother clove. The seeds become available from June to October. Fruits are allowed to ripe on the tree itself and drop down naturally. Such fruit are collected from the ground and sown directly in nursery or soaked in water overnight and the pericarp removed before sowing. They lose their viability within one week after harvest under normal conditions and hence they must be sown immediately after collection from a tree. The second method gives quicker and higher germination. Big sized seeds generally give higher percent of germination.\n\n\n<b>3.Nursery practices</b>\n\nBeds for sowing seeds are of 15 to 20 cm height, one metre width and a convenient length. The beds should be made of loose soils and over which a layer of sand may be spread (about 5 to 8cm thick). Seeds are sown at 2 to 3 cm spacing and a depth of about 2cm. The seedbeds have to be protected from direct sunlight. The germination commences in about 10 to 15 days and may last for about 40 days. In higher elevations, germination is delayed considerably, often requires 60 days. The germinated seedlings are transplanted in polythene bags 30cm x 15 cm) containing a mixture of good soil, sand and well decomposed cowdung (in the ratio of about 3:3:1). The seedlings are ready for transplanting in the field when they are 18 to 24 months old. The nurseries are usually shaded and irrigated daily to ensure uniform stand.\n\n\n<b>4.Land Preparation and Planting</b>\n\nEastern and northeastern hill slopes, well drained valleys and river banks are ideal for clove. The area selected for raising clove plantations is cleared of scrub growth before monsoon and pits of 60 to 75 cm 3 are dug at a spacing of 6 to 7 meters. The pits are partially filled with topsoil. The seedlings are transplanted in the main field during the beginning of rainy seasons, in June-July, and in low lying areas, towards the end of the monsoon, in September-October. Cloves prefer partial shade.\n\n\n<b>5.Manuring</b>\n\nClove trees are to be manured regularly and judiciously for their proper growth and flowering as given below:\n\n\n<b>6.Irrigation</b>\n\nIrrigation is necessary in the initial stages. In places where pronounced drought is normally experienced, pot watering is recommended to save the plants in the initial two or three years. Subsoil irrigation using 20cm length mud tubes or bamboo tubes with the helpful to save the plants during acute summer. Although the trees can survive without irrigation, it is advantageous to irrigate the grown up trees for proper growth and yield.\n\n\n<b>7.Harvesting</b>\n\nClove tree begins to yield from the seventh or eighth year after planting and full bearing stage is attained after about 15 to 20 years. The flowering season is September-October in the plains and December to February at high altitudes. Flower buds are produced on young flush. It takes about 4 to 6 months for the buds to become ready for harvest. At this time, they are less than 2cm long. The optimum stage for picking clove buds is indicated by the change in the colour from green to slightly pinkish tinge. The matured clove buds are carefully picked with hand. Care should be taken to pick the buds at the correct time, as otherwise the quality of the cured produce will be lost to a considerable extent. When the trees are tall and the clove bunches are beyond the reach, platform ladders are used for harvesting. Bending the branches or knocking down the bud clusters with sticks is not desirable as these practices affect the future bearing of the tree.\n\n\n<b>8.Curing</b>\n\nThe harvested flower buds are separated from the clusters by hand and spread in the drying yard for drying. It takes normally 4 to 5 days for drying. The correct stage of drying is reached when the stem of the bud is dark brown and the rest of the bud lighter brown in colour. Well dried cloves will be only about one-third of the weight of the original. About 11,000 to 15,000 dried cloves make one kilogram.\n\n\n<b>9.Yield</b>\n\nClove often experiences irregular or alternate bearing tendency. A well maintained full grown tree under favorable conditions may give 4 to 8 kg of dried buds. The average annual yields after 15th year may be taken as 2 kg per tree. Clove oil, the spice determining factor, is about 16 to 21 % in the buds. The oil contains 70 to 90 % of free eugenol and 5 to 12 % of eugenyl acetate.
    </string>

    <string name="Ginger_info"><b>Introduction</b>\n\nGinger is an important spice and used in different forms such as raw ginger, dry ginger, bleached dry ginger, ginger powder oleoresin, ginger beer, ginger candy, ginger wine etc. Kerala is the major ginger growing state. Other major ginger growing states are Orissa, Meghalaya, Himachal Pradesh and Karnataka. Ginger grows in warm and humid climate.\n\n\n<b>1.RequirementClimate</b>\n\nGinger can be grown both under rainfed and irrigated conditions. A moderate rainfall at the sowing time till the rhizomes sprout, fairly heavy and well distributed showers during the growing period and dry weather for about a month before harvesting are necessary.\n\n\n<b>2.Soil</b>\n\nGinger thrives the best in well drained soils like sandy or clay loam, red loam, or lateritic loam. A friable loam rich in humus is ideal. It may not be desirable to grow ginger in the same site year after year.\n\n\n<b>3.Preparation of land planting</b>\n\nThe land is to be ploughed 4to5 times or dug thoroughly to bring the soil to fine tilth. Weeds, stubbles, roots etc removed. Beds of about one meter width, 15cm height and of any convenient length are prepared at an inter-space of 50cm in between beds. In case of irrigated crops, ridges are formed 40cm apart.\n\n\n<b>4.Varieties</b>\n\nThey are generally named after the localities or places where they are grown. Common cultivars are Maran, Assam and Rio-de-Janeiro, Suprabha, Suruchi, Suravi, Himagiri, China, Himachal, Nadia, HSR-Varada.\n\n\n<b>5.Season</b>\n\nThe best time for planting ginger in West Coast of India is during the first fortnight of May with the receipt of pre-monsoon showers. Under irrigated conditions, it can be planted well in advance during the middle of February or early March.\n\n\n<b>6.Propagation</b>\n\nGinger is always propagated by rhizomes. Carefully preserved seeds rhizomes are cut into small pieces of 2.5 to 5cm length weighing 20 to 25g each having one or two good buds. The seed rate varies from region to region and with the method of cultivation adopted. The seed rhizomes are treated with 0.3% Dithane M to 45 (3g in one litre of water) for 30 min, drained and planted at a spacing of 20 to 25cm along the rows and 20 to 25cm between the rows.\n\n\n<b>7.Manuring</b>\n\nAt the time of planting, well decomposed and dried cattle manure or compost at the rate of 25 to 30 tonnes per hectare is to be applied. It may be applied prior to planting or applied in planting pits at the time of planting. Application of neem cake at 2 tonnes per hectare at the time of planting helps in reducing the incidence of rhizome rot of ginger. In case of fertilizer 25bags per hectare 7:10:5 (bone meal) applied before planting. And 2 to 2.5 months after planting 5 bags per hectare of Diammonium Phosphate (DAP) should be applied by mixing in the soil and also 2.5 bags urea per hectare.\n\n\n<b>8.Weeding</b>\n\nWeeding is done just before fertilizer application and mulching. Two or three weedings are required depending on the intensity of weed growth.\n\n\n<b>9.Crop rotation and mixed cropping</b>\n\nGinger is commonly rotated with other crops. The crops most commonly rotated with ginger are tapioca, chillies, dry paddy in rainfed areas and ragi, groundnut, maize and vegetables, red gram and castor.\n\n\n<b>10.Harvesting and curing</b>\n\nThe crop is ready for harvest in about eight months time when the leaves turn yellow, and start drying up gradually. The clumps are lifted carefully with a spade or digging fork, and the rhizomes are separated from the dried up leaves, roots and adhering soft. For making vegetables ginger, harvesting is done from 16 months onwards. The rhizomes are thoroughly washed in water twice or thrice and sun-dried for a day. The average yield of fresh ginger per hectare varies with varieties ranging 15 to 25 tonnes.\n\n\n<b>11.Preservation of seed rhizomes</b>\n\nFor seed materials, big and healthy rhizomes from disease free plants are selected immediately after the harvest. For this purpose, healthy and disease-free clumps are marked in the field when the crop is 6-8months old and still green. The seed rhizomes are treated with a solution containing 0.1% quinalphos and 0.3% Dithane-M-45 for 30 min. Drain the solution and dry the rhizomes under shade. The seed rhizomes are stored in pits of convenient size in sheds.

    </string>

    <string name="Black_info"><b>1.Introduction</b>\n\nBlack pepper(Piper nigrum L.), the king of spices, belongs to the family Piperaceae.It is obtained from the perennial climbing vine, Piper nigrum which is indigenous to thetropical forests of Western Ghats of South India. It is one of the important and earliestknown spices produced and exported from India. India accounts for 54% of the totalarea under pepper in the world but its share of production is only 26.6 %.It is a climbing evergreen plant and grows to a height of 10 m or more. The vines branch\n\n\n<b>2.Cultivation</b>\n\nhorizontally from the modes and do not attain length, but the fully-grown vines completely cover the standard presenting the appearance of bush. The leaves are broadly lanceolate, but wide variations occur in leaf shape and are arranged alternately. The inflorescence is a catkin produced at the nodes opposite to the upper leaves. Flowers are very minute. Monoecious or dioecious or hermophrodite forms occur in different varieties. The fruit is a single seeded berry, which has a thin,soft pericarp surriounding the seed. It takes approximately six months to mature after flowering. Sometimes, spike shedding occurs to the extent of 14 to 65 % causing considerable loss. Spraying of IAA 50 ppm or planofix 50 ppm and orzinc 0.5 % at the time of berry setting stage reduces spike shedding.\n\n\n<b>3.Climate and soil Requirement</b>\n\nPepper is a humid tropic plant, which requires adequate rainfall and humidity. The hot and humid climate of submountanous tracts of Western Ghats and Eastern Ghats is ideal for its growth. It grows successfully between 20o north and south latitude and from sea level up to 1500 meters above MSL. The temperature ranges between 10o and 40oC. A well-distributed annual rainfall of 125 to 200 cm is considered ideal for pepper.\nPepper can be grown in a wide range of soils such as clay loam, red loam, sandy loam and lateritic soils with a pH of 4.5 to 6.0, though in its natural habitat, it thrives best on virgin soil rich in organic matter.\n\n\n<b>4.Varieties</b>\n\nMajority of the cultivated types of pepper are monoecious. Over 75 cultivars of pepper are being cultivated in India. Karimunda is the most popular of all the established cultivars of pepper among the growers of Kerala. The other important cultivars are Kottanadan, Narayakkodi, Aimpiriyan, Neelamundi, Kuthiravally, Balancotta, Kalluvally, Malligesara and Uddagare.\n\n\n<b>5.Propagation</b>\n\nPepper is propagated by cuttings raised mainly from the runner shoots. Cuttings from the lateral branches are seldom used, since in addition to reduction in the number of fruiting shoots, the vines raised from them are generally short lived and bushy in habit. However, rooted lateral branches are useful in raising pepper in pots.Runner shoots from high yielding and healthy vines are kept coiled on wooden pegs fixed at the base of the vine to prevent the shoots from coming in contact with soil and striking roots. The runner shoots are separated from the vine in February-March and after trimming the leaves, cuttings of 2 to 3 nodes each are planted either in nursery beds or polythene bags filled with fertile soil. Cuttings from middle 1 by 3 of the shoots are desirable as they are high yielding. Adequate shade is to be provided and irrigated frequently. The cuttings will strike roots and become ready for planting in May to June.\n\n\n<b>6.Selection of site</b>\n\nWell drained level land and hill slopes are suitable for growing pepper. When grown on a slopy land, the slopes facing south should be avoided and the lower half of north and north eastern slopes are preferred for planting: so that the vines are not subjected to the scorching effect of the sun during summer.\n\n\n<b>7.Cropping method</b>\n\nPepper is grown as monocrop as well as a mixed crop. Large scale cultivation of pepper as monocrop is done on hill slopes by clearing jungle lands and planting standards for the vines to climb on. As a mixed crop, it is grown with arecanut, coconut, mango, jack etc. where these trees serve as standards for the pepper vines. Pepper is also a suitable intercrop in coffee estates where the shade trees as good standards for them.\n\n\n<b>8.Planting</b>\n\nPepper cuttings are generally planted with the onset of the southwest monsoon. Planting can also be done during the north east monsoon wherever it is regular and well distributed. When pepper is grown as pure crop, pits of 0.5 m cube are dug at a spacing of 2.5 x 2.5 m and Erythrina stem cuttings of 2m length or its two years old seedlings are planted on receipt of early monsoon showers. With the onset of regular rains, 2 or 3 rooted cuttings are planted around the base of the standard nearly 30 cm away. But in the case of coconut and arecanut which have a thick intercoiled root net close to the trunk, pepper cuttings are to be planted 100 to 120 cm away from the tree trunk which are about 8 to 9 m high. Initially, the vines may be allowed to climb on a stick or pole about 2 m tall, which is tied to the trunk in a slanting position. After one year, when the vine has attained sufficient length it may be separated from the temporary stake and the lower leaves may be nipped off. A narrow trench of 15 cm deep and wide should be prepared from the base of the vine to the base of the tree trunk. The vine may be placed in the trench in such a way that the growing tips it tied to the trunk while the other parts of vine is covered with the soil. A small ridge is formed over the trench which should not be disturbed while doing intercultural operations to the palm.\n\n\n<b>9.Cultural practices</b>\n\nAs the cuttings grow, the shoots are tied to the standards as often as required. The young vines should be protected from hot sun during summer months by providing them with artificial shade. Regulation of shade by lopping the branches of standards is necessary not only for providing optimum light to the vines but also for enabling the standards to grow straight. Adequate mulch with green leaf saw dust or coir dust or organic matter should be given towards the end of northeast monsoon. The base of the vines should bot be disturbed to avoid root damage.During the second year, practically the same cultural practices are repeated. However, lopping of the standards should be done carefully from the fourth year onwards, not only to regulate the height of the standards, but also to shade the pepper vines optimally. Excessive shading during flowering and fruiting encourages pest infestation. Pruning the top of the vine after it has reached the required height i.e. 6 m is normally practised when it is trained on standards like silver oak, coconut, arecanut for convenience of picking. From the fourth year, usually two diggings are given one during May-June and the other towards the end of southwest monsoon in October-November. Growing cover crops like Calapogonium mucanoides, Mimosa invisa are also recommended under West Coast conditions.\n\n\n<b>10.Harvesting and curing</b>\n\nPepper vines start yielding usually from the 3rd or 4th year. The vines flower in May-June. It takes 6 to 8 months from flowering to ripening stage. Harvesting is done from the November to February in the plains and January to march in the hills. When one or two berries on the spike turn bright or red, the whole spike is plucked.Berries are separated from the spikes by rubbing them between the hands or trampling them under the feet. After the separation, the berries are dried in the sun for 7 to 10 days until the outer skin becomes black and shrunken and assumes the characteristic wrinkled appearance of commercial black pepper. For making good quality black pepper of uniform colour, the separated berries are collected in a perforated bamboo basket or vessel and the basket with the berries is dipped in boiling water for one minute. The basket is then taken out and drained. The treated berries are sun dried on a clean bamboo mat or cement floor.White pepper of commerce is prepared by removing the outer skin and the pulp below it before drying the berries. Spikes with fully ripe berries are filled in gunny bags and steeped in flowing water for about 7 days. Outer rind of the berries is then removed by rubbing them with hands in a bucket of water and further cleaning the seeds with fresh water. The cleaned seeds are dried for 3 to 4 days. The seeds which are now dull white in colour are further cleaned by winnowing and polishing them by rubbing with a cloth. The recovery of white pepper is about 25 % of ripe berries while that of black pepper is about 33 %.\n\n\n<b>11.Yield</b>\n\nPepper vines attain full bearing stage in the 7th or 8th year after planting and it starts declining after 20 to 25 years and replanting has to be done thereafter. One-hectare plantation of 7 to 8 years old gives about 800 to 1000 kg of black pepper.
    </string>

    <string name="address">AgriGrow Technologies Pvt.Ltd.\nSurvey 71/5, 10th KM,\nState Highway 64, Maniapl\nKarnataka,Udupi 567101</string>

    <string name="about">AgriGrow with a bunch of professionals dreaming\nabout making agriculture more sustainable both\necologically and economically quick with\nhelp of technology.</string>

    <string name="Mango_info"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nNeelum, Bangalora, Alphonso, Rumani, Banganapalli, Kalepad, Peter, PKM 1, PKM 2, Sendura, Jahangir, Mulgoa, Himayuddin, Paiyur 1, Mallika, Amrapali and Salem Bangalora, Arka Anmol, Arka Aruna, Arka Neelkiran, Arka Puneeth and Sindhu are popular varieties in mango.\n\n\n<b>2.Varieties </b>\n\nBanganapalli, Bangalora, Neelum, Rumani, Mulgoa, Alphonso, Senthura, Kalepad, Imam Pasand\n\n\n<b>3.Soil and climate</b>\n\n
Ideal soil for mango is red loamy. Good drainage is preferable for better establishment. Ideal pH range is from 6.5 to 8.0.\n\n\n<b>4.Season of planting</b>\n\nPlanting spreads from July to December.\n\n\n<b>5.Planting material</b>\n\nApproach and epicotyl grafts are used for planting.\n\n\n<b>6.Field preparation</b>\n\nDig pits of 1 m x 1 m x 1 m. Fill in with topsoil mixed with 10 kg of FYM and 100 g per pit.\n\n\n<b>7.Spacing</b>\n\n
Adopt any one of the following spacing depending on requirements.\nUnder conventional system of planting: 7to10 m either way\nHigh Density Planting : 5m x 5 m  (400 plants perha)\nDouble hedge row system : Adopt  a spacing of  5m x  5m within double rows and 10m between successive double rows (266 plantsperha)\n\n\n<b>8.Planting</b>\n\nGrafts are planted in the centre of pit with ball of earth intact followed by watering and staking. The graft union must be 15 cm above the ground level.\n\n\n<b>9.Irrigation</b>\n\nRegular watering is recommended till establishment. Under conventional irrigation systems, weekly irrigation is essential. However, under microtoirrigation the requirement is restricted to onetothird of the water required for conventional method.\n\n\n<b>10.Canopy management:</b>Remove root stock sprouts and low lying branches nearer to ground to facilitate easy cultural operations. Remove overlapping, intercrossing, diseased, dried and weak branches in old trees to get good sunlight and aeration.  Carry out judicious pruning of the internal branches during August – September, once in three years.  Do not allow flowering up to three years by removing the inflorescences as and when they appear.  Retain two healthy shoots by trimming away the weak shoots among the crowded terminal shoots during AugusttoSeptember annually. Prune back 20 cm of annual growth of the terminals immediately after harvest.Top working of senile orchards for rejuvenation:Use scions of choice varieties like Alphonso and Banganapalli for top working. Behead the trees to be top worked portion during Julyto August leaving the main trunk at a convenient height and allow for new shoots to develop.  Adopt cleft method of grafting or softwood grafting on the emerging shoots on the main stem from the cut end during Septemberto October.\n\n\n<b>11.Growth regulators</b>\n\nNAA at 20 ppm is sprayed at flowering to increase the fruit retention.  During February 0.5 Percentage Urea (5 gperlit.) or 1 Percentage Potassium Nitrate (10gperlit.) may be sprayed to induce flowering, if trees do not flower by that time. Spraying of 2 Percentage KNO3 at mustard size will increase the fruit set and retention of fruits.Application of Paclobutrazol at 10 g a.i. for nontobearing trees during first fortnight of September will induce flowering and fruitset yield during off y\n\n\n<b>12.Hopper</b>\n\nSpraying two rounds of acephate 75 SPat 1gperlit or phosalone 35 EC  at 1.5 mlperlit or carbaryl 50 WP 2 gperlit or phosphamidon 40SL 2 mlperlit of water will control hopper. First at the time of panicle emergence and the second two weeks after first spray. Wettable sulphur at 2 gperlit may be sprayed after spraying carbaryl to avoid mite resurgence. Phosphamidon + neem oil 5 mlperlit of water can be mixed with any insecticides for the control of hopper and shoot webber.\n\n\n<b>13.Harvest Season</b>\n\nHarvest spreads from March to June.
</string>

    <string name="Banana_info"><b>1.Introduction</b>\n\nBanana is the fruit of a plant of the genus Musa (family Musaceae), which is cultivated primarily for food and secondarily for the production of fibre used in the textile industry are also cultivated for ornamental purposes. Almost all the modern edible parthenocarpic bananas come from the two wild species – Musa acuminataMusa balbisiana. The scientific names of bananas are Musa acuminata, Musa balbisiana or hybrids of Musa acuminata and balbisiana, depending on their genomic constitution.Bananas are vigorously growing, monocotyledonous herbaceous plants.The banana is not a tree but a high herb that can attain up to 15 meters of height. The cultivars vary greatly in plant an d fruit size, plant morphology, fruit quality and disease and insect resistance. Most bananas have a sweet flavor when ripe; exceptions to this are cooking bananas and plantains. Plantains are hybrid bananas in which the male flowering axis is either degenerated, lacking, or possess relicts of male flowers. Plantains are always cooked before consumption and are higher in starch than bananas. The two groups of plantains, French and Horn, produce fewer fruit per plant than sweet bananas. The groups differ in whether the male parts of the inflorescence are present or abse\n\n\n<b>2.Varieties</b>\n\n\n<b>Dessert </b>\n\nRobusta, Dwarf Cavendish, Grand Naine, Rasthali, Vayal vazhai, Poovan, Nendran, Red Banana, Karpooravalli, Co.1, Matti, Sannachenkadali, Udayam and Neypoovan are popular varieties in banana. Cavendish groups are generally pre fered in export market.\n<b>Culinary </b>Monthan, Vayal vazhai, Ash Monthan and Chakkia are cultivated for culinary purpose. Nendran is a dual purpose variety used for dessert and culinary.\n<b>Hill areas</b>The popular varieties of bananas suitable for hilly areas are Virupakshi, Sirumalai and Namarai. Red Banana, Manoranjitham (Santhana vazhai) and Ladan are also cultivated in hills.\n<b>Wetland</b>Form trenches in between alternate rows and cross trenches at every 5th row. The trenches are periodically deepened and the soil is spread over the bed.  Surface diggings may be given at bitomonthly intervals and desuckering at monthly intervals. Remove the male flower a week after opening of last hand. Prop plants at or prior to flowering. Cover the peduncle with flag leaf and the bunch with leaves to avoid sunscald. For ratoon crops in respect of Poovan, Monthan and Rasthali allow the follower at flowering stage of the mother plant and remove the other suckers during harvest.\n<b>Perennial banana</b>Surface digging should be done once in two months. One deep digging may be given during January – February. Other operations should be done as similar in garden land.\n<b>Hill banana</b>Give four forkings in January, April, July and October. Remove outer sheaths to keep the corm inside the soil and ward off borer. Maintain two bearing plants and two followers per clump along the contour.\n\n\n<b>3.Growth regulators</b>\n\nTo improve the grade of bunches 2, 4toD at 25 ppm (25 mgperlit) may be sprayed on Poovan and Co 1 banana after the last hand has emerged. This will also help to remove seediness in Poovan variety. Spray CCC 1000 ppm at 4th and 6th month after planting.\n\n\n<b>4.Micronutrients</b>\n\nSpray micronutrients viz., ZnSO4 (0.5 Percentage), FeSO4 (0.2 Percentage), CuSO4 (0.2 Percentage) and H3BO3 (0.1 Percentage) and 3, 5 and 7 MAP to increase yield and quality of banan\n\n\n<b>5.Diseases</b>\n\nSigatoka leaf spot\nRemove affected leaves and burn. Spray any one of the following fungicides commencing from November at monthly interval.  Carbendazim 1 gperlit., Benomyl 1 gperlit., Mancozeb 2 gperlit., Copper oxychloride 2.5 gperlit., Ziram 2 mlperlit,\nChlorothalonil 2 gperlit. Alternation of fungicides for every spray prevents fungicidal resistance. Always add 5 ml of wetting agent like Sandovit, Triton AE, Teepol etc. per 10 lit of spray fluid.\n\n<b>Panama Disease</b>\nUproot and destroy severely affected plants. Apply lime at 1 – 2 kg in the pits after removal of the affected plants. In the field, Panama wilt disease can be prevented by corm injection methods. A small portion of soil is removed to expose the upper portion of the corm. An oblique hole at 45° angle is made to a depth of 10 cm. Immediately, a gelatin capsule containing 60 mg of Carbendazim or 3 ml of 2  Percentage Carbendazim solution or capsule application for 50 mg of Pseudomonas fluorescens is injected into the hole with the help of ‘corm injector’ on 2nd, 4th and 6th month after planting.</string>

    <string name="Sapota_info"><b>1.Varieties :</b>\n\nThe commercially cultivated arieties are (Click on the variety name to see the detailed Soil and climateIt is a tropical crop and can be grown up to an altitude of 1000 metres. It can be grown in all types of soils.\n\n\n<b>2.Planting materials</b>\n\n
Sapota can be propagated by approach grafting. Grafting can be done on Manilkhara hexandra  (Pala) rootstock.\n\n\n<b>3.Season of planting</b>\n\nThe ideal season of planting is June to December.\n\n\n<b>4.Spacing</b>\n\n8 x 8 m (156 plantsperha) for conventional planting.Adopt high density planting at 8 x 4 m (312 plants per ha) for high productivit\n\n\n<b>5.Leaf webber</b>\n\nLeaf webber can be controlled by spraying Phosalone 35 EC 2 mlperlit.\n\n\n<b>6.Hairy caterpillars</b>\n\nHairy caterpillars are effectively controlled by spraying Chloropyriphos 20 EC or Quinalphos 25EC or Phosalone 35 EC 2 mlperlit of water.\n\n\n<b>7.Bud worm</b>\n\nSpraying of Phosalone 35 EC 2 mlperlit or Phosphamidon 40 SL 2 mlperlit or Quinalphos 25EC 2 mlperlit or Carbaryl 50 WP at1 gperlit or Neem Seed Kernel Extract 5  Percentage controls the bud worms effectively.\n\n\n<b>8.Diseases</b>\n\n
Sooty mouldSooty mould can be controlled by spraying starch solution. The required concentration can be prepared by boiling 1 Kg maida or starch with 5 lit of water. After cooling, dilute the solution with 20 litres of water. Avoid spraying during cloudy weather.\n\n\n<b>9.Harvest</b>\n\nA mature fruit is dull brown in colour and the colour immediately below the skin when scratched is of lighter shade, while in the immature fruits it is green.  The mature fruits are harvested by hand picking.\n\n\n<b>10.Ripening</b>\n\n
Ripen the fruits by keeping a beaker containing 5000 ppm Ethrel + 10 g NaOH pellets in an air tight chamber. (5 ml Ethrel in one lit of water is 5000 ppm).\n\n\n<b>11.Yield</b>\n\n
Depending up on the variety the fruit yield ranges from 20 to 25 tperhaperyear.
</string>

    <string name="Papaya_info"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nCO 1, CO 2, CO 3, CO 4, CO 5, CO 6, CO 7, CO 8, Coorg Honey dew and Surya.CO 3, CO 7 and Surya are gynodioecious (bisexual + female) types highly suitable for table purpose and CO 2, CO 5 and CO 6 are dualtopurpose varieties for table and papain production.\n\n\n<b>2.Soil and climate</b>\n\nIt is a tropical fruit and grows well in regions where summer temperature ranges from 35°C to 38°C. Tolerates frost and comes up to an elevation of 1200 m above mean sea level. Well drained soils of uniform texture are highly preferable to avoid the collar rot disease.\n\n\n<b>3.Sowing</b>\n\n500 g of seeds is required for planting one ha. JunetoSeptember is the best season for planting.  Avoid planting in rainy season.\n\n\n<b>4.Nursery</b>\n\nTreat the seeds with Captan at 2 gperkg of seeds. Dibble four seeds in polythene bags in depth not exceeding one cm.  Keep the polythene bags in partial shade. Watering can be done with the help of rose can. Seedlings will be ready in about 60 days. \n\n\n<b>5.Planting</b>\n\nPlant the seedlings at 1.8 m either ways in pits of 45 cm x 45 cm x 45 cm size.\n\n\n<b>6.Irrigation</b>\n\nIrrigate copiously after planting. Irrigate the field once in a week\n\n\n<b>7.Application of fertilizers</b>\n\nApply FYM 10 Kgperplant as basal and 50 g in each of N, P and K per plant at bitomonthly intervals from the third month of planting after removing unwanted sex forms. Apply 20 g in each of Azospirillum and Phosphobacterium at planting again six months after planting.\n\n\n<b>8.Fertigation technique</b>\n\n
Apply 10 litres of water per day + 13.5 g urea and 10.5 g muriate of  potashper week through drip irrigation and soil application of super phosphate 300g  per plant at bimonthly intervals starting from 3to4 months after planting immediately after  thinning of plants is recommended.\n\n\n<b>9.After cultivation</b>\n\nMale trees should be removed after the emergence of inflorescence maintaining one male tree for every 20 female trees for proper fruitset. In each pit only one vigorously growing femaleperhermaphrodite tree should be retained and other plants should be removed. In gynodioecious type like (Co 3  and  Co 7) keep one hermophrodite typeperpit and remove female trees. \n\n\n<b>9.Micronutrients</b>\n\nSpray ZnSO4 0.5 Percentage + H2BO3 0.1 Percentage during 4th and 8th month to increase growth and yield characters.\n\n\n<b>10.Plant protection</b>\n\nNematodes\nTo control the nematode infestation in nursery, apply Carbofuran 3 G at 1 gperpolythene bag after germinationPapain extraction\nPapain has several industrial uses, the important one being in brewing industries. It is used as “meat tenderiser” and in textile and leather “sanforization” processes and drugs.The method of extraction of papain from papaya fruits is simple. The latex should be tapped from immature papaya fruits. Select 75 to 90 days old fruits.  On the selected fruit, give incisions (cut) with a razor blade or stainless steel knife. The cuts should be given from stalk to tip of the fruit. The depth of the cut should not be more than 0.3 cm.  Four such cuts are given spaced equally on the fruit surface. Tap the latex early in the morning and complete the tapping before 10.00 a.m.  Repeat the tapping four times on the same fruit at an interval of three days. The cut should be given on the fruit surface in places not covered by previous cuts. The latex collected from all the trees in a day should be pooled, shade dried in an aluminium pan or tray and passed through a 50 mesh sieve to remove all foreign matter. In large plantations, vacuum driers can be adopted with advantage. Papain produced by artificial heating will have better colour and high quality. Add potassium metatobitosulphite (KMS) at 0.5  Percentage for better colour and keeping quality.\nThe latex should be dried very rapidly at temperatures of 50°  to 55° C.  Stop drying when the dried product comes off as flakes having a porous texture.  Powder the dried papain by means of wooden mallets or in electrically operated granulators and sieve the powder through 10 mesh sieve. Pack the powder in polythene bags in convenient quantities and seal them. Put the sealed bags in a tin container and seal it after evacuating air. Exposure to air deteriorates the quality of papain and vacuum sealing is therefore necessary. For large scale manufacture of papain, vacuum sealing machine and a granulator will be useful.\nThe green papaya fruits after extraction of papain can be used for pectin manufacture and “tutty – fruity” or they can be allowed to ripen and made into other products. The Co.2 and Co.5 varieties of papaya released by Tamil Nadu Agricultural University, Coimbatore are ideal for papain production. Tamil Nadu Agricultural University, Coimbatore, supplies pure seeds of these varieties.\n\n\n\n<b>Yield</b>\n\nThe yield of crude papain is as follows:\nCO 2  :  600 kgperha\n CO 5  :  800 Kgperha\n
</string>

    <string name="Guava"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nAllahabad, Lucknow 46, 49, Arka Amulya, Arka Mridula, Banaras, Baptla, Arka Kiran, Lalit and TRY (G)to1 are the suitable varieties for cultivation.\n\n\n<b>2.Soil</b>\n\n and climateGuava grows well both in wet and dry regions but it does better under irrigation in the dry tracts. It can be grown up to 1000 m altitude.  Well drained soils are the best suited for guava cultivation. It can tolerate salinity and alkalinity.  In saline soils add 3 Kg Gypsumperplant during planting and once in three years after planting to overcome the problem. \n\n\n<b>3.Planting</b>\n\n materialLayers are used as planting material.\n\n\n<b>4.Spacing</b>\n\nA spacing 5 to 6m in either way is generally followed.\n\n\n<b>5.Planting</b>\n\nPlant the layers with the ball of earth in the centre of pit of 45 cm x 45 cm x 45 cm size filled with FYM 10 Kg neem cake 1 Kg and top soil\n\n\n<b>6.Irrigation</b>\n\nIrrigate copiously immediately after planting, again on third day and afterwards once in 10 days or as and when necessary.\n\n\n<b>7.Manures and fertilizers</b>\n\nFYM 50 Kg and one Kg in each of N, P and K per tree in two split doses during March and October should be applied. To increase the yield, spray Urea 1  Percentage + Zinc sulphate 0.5 Percentage twice a year during March and October. To correct the boron deficiency (reduction in size of leaves and fruit cracking and hardening) spray 0.3 Percentage borax during flowering and fruit set stage.Micronutrients spray for controlling bronzing of leaves\n
A combined spray should be given containing ZnSO4, MgSO4 and MnSo4 at 0.5 Percentage and CuSO4 and FeSO4 at 0.25  Percentage plus Teepol at 1ml per 5 lit of solution on various stages as \n\n\n<b>9.Intercropping</b>\n\nLegumes and short duration vegetable crops may be raised during pretobearing stage.\n\n\n<b>10.Aftercultivation</b>\n\nPruning of past season’s terminal growth to a length of 10to15 cm is to be done during SeptembertoOctober and February – March to encourage more laterals.  The erect growing branches are to be bent by tying on to pegs driven on the ground. Old unproductive but healthy trees can be rejuvenated may be either pollarded or cut back to 75 cm from ground level or dehorned by cutting the secondary branches at a distance of 75 cm from their origin.\n\n\n<b>11.Plant protection</b>\n\nTea mosquito bug\nSpray Quinalphos 25 EC at the rate of 2 mlperlit or Malathion 50 EC at the rate of 1 mlperlit or Monocrotophos 36 WSC at 2mlperlit or neem oil 3  Percentage. Spraying should be done in early mornings or late evenings, at least four times at 21 days interval during fruiting season.Aphids\nSpray Monocrotophos 36 WSC at 1mlperlit or Dimethoate 30 EC at 2 mlperlit to control aphids.Mealy bug\nThe mealy bugs can be controlled by spraying Triazophos at 2mlperlit + neem oil 5 ml or phosalone 0.05 Percentage + neem oil 5 ml.  Release of Cryptolaemus montrouzieri beetles (Coccinellid beetles) at 10 beetles pertree is also recommended.Fruit fly\nSpray Quinalphos 25 EC or Malathion 50 EC at 1 mlperlit four times at 15 days interval. Use polythene bags fish meal trap with 5 gm of wet fish meal + 1 ml. dichlorvos in cotton. 50 traps are requiredperha, fish meal and Dichlorvos soaked cotton are to be renewed once in 20 and 7 days respectively.Safe waiting period
        For Monocrotophos 36 WSCto10 days and for Malathion 50 EC – 9 days.\n\n\n<b>12.Diseases</b>\n\nRed rust\nSpray Copper oxy chloride 2.5 g perlit or Bordeaux mixture 0.6  Percentage or Wettable sulphur 2 gperlit to control red rust.\n\n\n<b>13.Harvest</b>\n\n
        Layers come to bearing in 2 to 3 years. The first crop can be harvested during February – July and the second one during September – January.\n\n
    The crop yields about 25 tperha.
</string>

    <string name="Lemon_info"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nLocal varieties, PKM1, Vikram and Rasraj are the popular varieties in acid lime. \n\n\n<b>2.Soil and climate</b>\n\nThe crop can be cultivated in both Tropical and subtropical climate. It can be grown up to 1000 m above MSL. Deep well drained loamy soils are best suited for the cultivation.\n\n\n<b>2.Season</b>\n\nThe planting is done from December – February and June – September.\n\n\n<b>3.Planting</b>\n\nHealthy seedlings are planted during June to December at 5 to 6 m spacing in 75 cm x 75 cm x 75 cm pits.\n\n\n<b>4.Irrigation</b>\n\nIrrigate copiously after planting. After establishment of the crop, irrigation is given at 7 – 10 days interval. Water stagnation should be avoided\n\n\n<b>5.Manures and fertilizers per plant</b>\n\nN is applied in two doses during March and October.  FYM, P2O5 and K2O are to be applied in October.\n\n\n<b>6.After cultivation</b>\n\nThe branches of main stem up to 45 cm from ground level have to be removed. Green leaves at 30 kg per tree are applied once in 3 months.\n\n\n<b>7.Intercropping</b>\n\nLegumes and vegetable crops can be raised during pretobearing age.\n\n\n<b>8.Growth regulator</b>\n\nTo increase the fruit set, spray 2, 4 – D at 20 ppm during flowering stage. For fruit retention, spray 2, 4 – D at 20 ppm or NAA at 30 ppm after fruit set (marble size).\n\n\n<b>9.Plant protection</b>\n\nPests Leaf minerThe pest can be controlled by spraying Dichlorvos 76 WSC at 1 mlperlit or Dimethoate 30 EC at 2 mlperlit or Monocrotophos 36 WSC at 1.5 mlperlit or neem seed kernel extract (NSKE) at 50gperlit or 3  Percentage neem cake extract or neem oil.\n\n\n<b>Leaf caterpillar</b>\n\n
When the infestation is moderate to severe, Quinalphos25 EC at 2mlperlit is sprayed to control to control the pest. The larvae can be hand picked and destroyed.\n\n\n<b>Fruit sucking moth</b>\n\nTinospora weed host have to be destroyed. Bait with fermented molasses plus Malathion 50 EC at the rate of 1 mlperlit can be used for control. Bag the fruits with polythene bags punctured at the bottom. Apply smoke and set up light traps or food lures (pieces of citrus fruits) for control.\n\n\n<b>Shoot borer</b>\n\nPrune the withered shoots 4 cm below the dried portions and spray Monocrotophos 36 WSC at 1 mlperlit or Quinalphos25 EC at 1.5 mlperlit or Carbaryl 50 WP at 2 gperlit.\n\n\n<b>Stem borer</b>\n\nThe branches containing grubs have to be pruned. Plugging the fresh holes with cotton soaked in Monocrotophos solution mixed at 5 mlper20 ml of water will also control the pest.\n\n\n<b>10.Nematodes</b>\n\nApply Carbofuran 3 G at 75 gpertree to control citrus nematodes in severe infestations. Apply 20 g Pseudomonas fluorescens formulation per tree at a depth of 15 cm and 50 cm away from the trunk once in four months. Soil application of Phorate at 2 g followed by drenching with 1  Percentage of Metalaxyl plus Mancozeb 72 WP at 50 mlper cuttingper poly bagper kg of nursery soil is done for controlling citrus decline.\n\n\n<b>11.Diseases</b>\n\n
Twig blight\nPrune dried twigs and spray 3 Percentage Copper oxychloride or 0.1 Percentage Carbendazim at monthly intervals to reduce the spread of disease.Scab \nSpray 1 Percentage Bordeaux mixture to control the disease. Canker\n Immediately after pruning one spray of Copper oxychloride (COC) 0.3 Percentage is done followed by 4 sprayings with Streptocyclin100 ppm + COC 1.5 kgperha at monthly intervals. Tristeza virus\nRemove the infected trees and destroy.  Spray Methyl demeton 25 EC or Monocrotophos at 1 mlperlit to control the aphids which spread the disease. Use pretoimmunized acid lime seedlings for planting.\n\n\n<b>12.Harvest</b>\n\n
    The crop starts bearing from 3rd year after planting.Post harvest treatment\n
    Treating the fruits with 4 Percentage wax emulsion followed by pretopacking in 200 gauge polythene bags with 1  Percentage ventilation improves the shelf life for more than 10 days.\n\n\n<b>13.Yield</b>\n\n
    The crop yields about 25 tperhaperyear.
    </string>

    <string name="Orange_info"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nThe commercially cultivated variety is Sathukudi.\n\n\n<b>2.Soil and climate</b>\n\nDeep well drained loamy soils are the best for the cultivation of Citrus. The pH of soil should be 6.5 to 7.5 and EC of water less than 1.0.  A dry climate with about 50 – 75 cm of rainfall from June – September and with well defined summer and winter season is ideal. Sweet orange comes up well in tropical zone below 500 m. The extreme of temperature are necessary for achieving higher yield.\n\n\n<b>3.Season</b>\n\nThe ideal season for cultivation of sweet orange is July to September.\n\n\n<b>4.Planting material</b>\n\n
Budded plants are the best planting materials. (Root Stock to Rangpur lime and rough lemon is mostly preferred).\n\n\n<b>5.Preparation of field</b>\n\nDig pits at 75 cm x 75 cm x 75 cm size at 7 x 7 m spacing. Fill up the pits with top soil and 10 kg of FYM. Plant the budded plants in the centre of the pits and stake it.\n\n\n<b>6.Irrigation</b>\n\nImmediately after planting irrigate copiously. Irrigations may be given once in 10 days. Avoid water stagnation near the plant during monsoon and cyclone periods.\n\n\n<b>7.Manures and fertilizers per plant</b>\n\nNitrogen has to be applied in two doses during March and October. However Farm yard manure, Phosphorous and Potash are to be applied in October.\n\n\n<b>8.After cultivation</b>\n\nAs intercultural operations remove the water shoots, rootstock sprouts, dead and diseased shoots. For higher productivity remove all the laterals up to 45 cm from ground level.\n\n\n<b>9.Intercropping</b>\n\nLegumes and vegetable crops can be raised as intercrop during pretobearing age to get additional income.\n\n\n<b>10.Harvest</b>\n\n
Yield of crop starts bearing from 5th year after planting and the economic yield can be obtained up to 20 years after planting.\n\n\n<b>11.Yield</b>\n\nDepending upon the variety and season the yield of crop varies from 25 to 30 tperha.
</string>

    <string name="Grapes_info"><b>1.Varieties:</b>\n\nMuscat (Panneer), Pachadraksha, AnabtoetoShahi, Thompson Seedless, Arka Shyam, Arka Kanchan, Arka Hans, Manik Chaman, Sonaka, Sharadh Seedless and Flame Seedless are normally cultivated.Muscat is grown in Tamil Nadu where the rainfall is low to moderate.\n\n\n<b>2.Soil and climate</b>\n\nThe crop performs best in welltodrained rich loamy soil with a pH of 6.5 to 7.0 with low water table with EC less than 1.0. Soil depth should be at least 1 m.\n\n\n<b>2.Field preparation and planting</b>\n\nTrenches of 0.6 m width and 0.6 m depth are to be dug at a distance of 3 m apart for Muscat and pits of 1m x 1m x 1m should be dug for other varieties. Welltodecomposed FYM or compost or green leaf manure has to be applied in the trenches or pits as the case may be and then covered with soil. Plant the rooted cuttings in JunetoJuly.\n\n\n<b>3.Spacing</b>\n\nThe adopted spacing is 3 x 2 m for Muscat and 4 x 3 m for other varieties.\n\n\n<b>4.Irrigation</b>\n\nIrrigate immediately after planting and on the 3rd day and then once in a week.  Withhold irrigation 15 days before pruning and also 15 days before harvest.\n\n\n<b>5.Pruning</b>\n\nIn general four bud level of pruning for Muscat, Pachadraksha, Bangalore Blue, AnabtoetoShahi and Arka hybrids and two bud level for Thompson Seedless may be adopted. It is better to decide the level of pruning as per bud forecasting technique.  Weak and immature canes should be pruned to one or two buds to induce vegetative growth.\n\n\n<b>6.Pruning Season</b>\n\nSummer crop\nPruning is done in December – January and harvesting in April – May.Monsoon crop\nPruning is done in MaytoJune and harvesting in AugusttoSeptember.\n\n\n<b>7.Special practices</b>\n\nTipping of shoots and tying of clusters in the pandal after the fruit set should be done.  The tendrils have to be removed. Nip the growing shoots of axillary buds and terminal buds at 12 to 15 buds. Fruit thinning is done in compact bunches by removing 20  Percentage of the berries at pea stage.Dip the clusters in solution containing Brassinosteroid 0.5 ppm and GA3 25 ppm at 10to12 days after fruit set to maintain vigour, yield and quality parameters.\n\n\n<b>8.Plant protection</b>\n\nPests<b>Nematodes</b>\n60 g of Carbofuran 3 G or Phorate 10 G granules per vine are applied a week before pruning and the plots are irrigated profusely.  The soil should not be disturbed for atleast 15 days. Thereafter normal manuring may be done.  Application of neemcake 200 gpervine also controls nematodes. Alternatively, application of Pseudomonas fluorescens formulation in talc containing 15 x 108 colony forming unitsperg, 30 cm away from base of the vine at least 15 cm depth at the time of pruning will also serve as a control measure.<b>Flea beetles</b>\nSpray Phosalone 35 EC (2mlperlit of water) after pruning and followed by two or three sprayings. The loose bark may be removed at the time of pruning to prevent egg laying.<b>Thrips</b>\nSpray Methyl demeton 25 EC or Dimethoate 30 EC at 2 mlperlit of water to control thrips.<b>Mealy bug</b>\nApply Quinalphos or Methyl parathion dust in the soil at 20 kgperha to kill the Phoretic ants. Spray Methyl demeton 25 EC or Monocrotophos 36 WSC at 2 mlperlit of water or spray Dichlorvos 76 WSC at 1 mlperlit with fish oil resin soap at 25 gperlit to control the pest.  Release Coccinellid beetle, Cryptolaemus montrouzieri at the rate of 10 per vine.<b>Stem girdler</b>\nSwab the trunk with Carbaryl 50 WP at 2 gmperlit to control the pest.\n\n\n<b>8.Diseases</b>\n\nPowdery mildewSpray 0.3 Percentage Wettable sulphur or dust Sulphur at 6to12 Kgperha in the morning hours to control the fungus.<b>Anthracnose</b>\nSpray 1  Percentage Bordeaux mixture or any other copper fungicide at 0.25  Percentage concentration. Depending upon the weather conditions the number of sprays has to be increased.<b>Downy mildew</b>\nSpray 1  Percentage Bordeaux mixture or any other copper fungicide at 0.25  Percentage concentration. Depending upon the weather conditions the number of sprays has to be increased.<b>Ripening</b>\nTo get uniform ripening in Muscat, spray the bunches with 0.2 Percentage Potassium sulphate (2 gperlit) at 20th day after berry set and another spray on 40th day.Dip the clusters of Thompson seedless and other seedless varieties at calyptra fall stage with 25 ppm GA (25 mgperlit) and repeat again at pepper stage to increase the length of berries.\n\n\n<b>9.Yield</b>\n\nSeedless : 15 tperhaperyear\nMuscat : 30 tperhaperyear\nPachadraksha  :  40 tperhaperyear\nAnabtoetoShahi and Arka hybrids :  20 tperhaperyear\n</string>

    <string name="Pineapple_info"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nKew, Mauritius and Queen are the commercially cultivated pineapple varieties in Tamil Nadu.\n\n\n<b>2.Soil and climate</b>\n\nMild tropical climate as found in the humid hill slopes is best suited for cultivation. This can also be grown in plains under shade i.e as intercropping system. Elevation from 500 m to 700 m is ideal for cultivation. A light well drained soil with pH 5.5 to 7.0 is highly preferable. Heavy soils can also be used for commercial cultivation if drainage facilities are available. \n\n\n<b>3.Spacing</b>\n\nPlant in double rows either in beds or in trenches with the plants into the second rows set in the middle of the plants in the first row. The spacing between two trenches will be 90 cm. Row to row spacing in the same bed per trench will be 60 cm and plant spacing within the row is 30 cm.\n\n\n<b>4.Planting</b>\n\nUse suckers and slips of 300to350 g weight for planting. Give a slanting cut to the suckers before planting and dip in Mancozeb 0.3  Percentage or Carbendazim 0.1 Percentage.\n\n\n<b>5.Method of propagation</b>\n\nPlanting season\nThe ideal season for planting is July – September\n<b>Manures and fertilizers</b>\nFYM 40to50 tperha, N 16 g, P 4 g and K 12 gperplant in two equal splits at 6th and 12th month after planting. Apply as foliar spray 0.5 Percentage to 1.0  Percentage sulphate of Zinc and Ferrous solutions at 15 days interval to overcome the deficiencies in the early crop phase.\n\n\n<b>6.Aftercultivation</b>\n\nTo have uniform flowering apply NAA 10 ppm + 2  Percentage urea (20 g in 1 lit of water) at 50 mlperplant poured into crown, or 2  Percentage urea + 0.04  Percentage Sodium carbonate + 20 ppm Ethephon (ethrel) at 50 mlperplant poured into the crown the when the crop attains 35 – 40 leaf stage. To increase the size of the fruit, 200 – 300 ppm NAA should be sprayed after fruit formation. To avoid calcium induced Iron chlorosis adequate shade should be given.\n\n\n<b>7.Harvest</b>\n\nFruits can be harvested from 18 to 24 months after planting. Slight colour change at the base of the fruit indicates maturity. \n\n\n<b>8.Yield</b>\n\nAn average of 50 tperha can be harvested from well maintained pineapple orchard. One plant crop and two ratoon crops are normally practiced in most of varieties and in Mauritius variety up to five crops can be taken.</string>

    <string name="Apple_info"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nThe varieties with warm winter resistance with low chilling requirements alone are suitable to the hills of Tamil Nadu.\n<b>Early varieties</b>\n\nThese varieties bears yield during April – May.\nIrish Peach and Zouches Pipin are popular early varieties.\n<b>Mid season varieties</b>\n\nThese varieties bears yield during June – July.\nThe popular mid season varieties are KKL 1, Carrington and Winterstein.\n<b>Late varieties</b>\n\nThese varieties bears yield during August – September.Rome Beauty, Parlin’s Beauty and KKL 1 are early varieties.\n\n\n<b>2.Soil and climate</b>\n\nRed lateritic soils with good drainage and high organic matter are more suitable. The soil pH should be around 5.8 to 6.2. Apple can be grown at an elevation of 1200 to 2000 m.\n\n\n<b>2.Season</b>\n\nPlanting spreads from June to December\n\n\n<b>3.Planting material</b>\n\nOne year old grafts with M.778 or M.779 as rootstocks can be used for planting.\n\n\n<b>4.Spacing</b>\n\nApple is normally planted at a spacing of 4 x 4 m in pits of 60 cm x 60 cm x 60 cm.\n\n\n<b>5.Irrigation</b>\n\nWatering is done until the plants get established.\n\n\n<b>6.Application of fertilizer</b>\n\nFor a bearing tree apply FYM 25 Kg, N 500 g and each one Kg of P and K per bearing tree.\n\n\n<b>7.Training and pruning</b>\n\nThe tree is trained to open centre system. Pruning done during November enables harvest during June – July and pruning during January will enable harvest during July – September.\n\n\n<b>8.Disease</b>\n\nTo control apple scab, the following spray schedule at various stages of the crop can be followed:\n1. Silver tip to green tip        : Captafol or Mancozeb or Captan 2 gperlit.\n2. Pink bud or after 15 days : Captan or Mancozeb 2 gperlit.\n3. Petal fall                         : Carbendazim 0.5 gperlit.\n4. 10 days after petal fall     : Captan or Mancozeb 2 gperlit.\n5. 14 days after fruit set       : Captafol 2 gperlit.\nAdd stickers like Triton AE or Teepol at 10 mlper10 lit of spray fluid.  Use low volume sprayersLichens\nSpray quick lime at 1 kgper20 lit of water after pruning to control lichens growth.\n\n\n\n<b>9.Yield</b>\n\nThe yield ranges between 10 – 20 kg per tree per year.  The tree starts bearing from 4th year of planting.</string>

    <string name="drone1">We provide services for spraying of\npesticides in agricultural fields with\nprecise and automated spraying. Our\ndrones can also be used for disinfectant\nspraying in large areas over a short\nperiod of time.</string>
    <string name="drone2">1. Sprays uniformly and covers one acre\nin 10 minutes.\n2. Increases the efficacy of pesticides\nand quick control of pests.\n3. It is less costly compared to the\ntraditional method of spraying.\n4. Reduces the risk of labors by avoiding\ndirect exposure to the pesticide.</string>


    <string name="Fennel_info"><b>Varieties</b>\n\nCO 1, UF 32, PF 35 and Gujarat Fennel 1.\n\n\n<b>Soil and climate</b>\n\nWell drained loamy soil or black or sandy soil rich in organic matter is suitable for fennel cultivation.\n\n\n<b>Climate</b>\n\nIt comes up well in fairly mild with frost free climate\n\n\n<b>Season:</b>\n\nHills: May to June.\n\n\n<b>Plains:</b>\n\nOctober to November.\n\n\n<b>Seed rate</b>\n\nFor direct sowing:    9 to 12 kg/ha.\nFor transplanting:    3 to 4 kg/ha – Nursery area 100 sq.m.\n\n\n\n<b>Spacing</b>\n\n5 to 6 weeks old seedlings are transplanted at 60 x 30 cm spacing.\n\n\n<b>Thinning</b>\n\nIn direct sown crop thin 4 – 5 weeks old seedlings to 25 – 30 cm spacing.\n\n\n<b>Irrigation</b>\n\nFirst irrigation should be given immediately after sowing, second on the third day and subsequent irrigations at 7 to 10 days intervals.\n\n\n<b>Yield</b>\n\n Two or three weedings are necessary. The plants are earthed up after 3 months. Pretoemergent application of Pendimethalin @ 1 kg a.i./ha and one hand weeding.\n\n\n<b>Plant protection</b>\n\nPestsAphidsAphids can be controlled by spraying Dimethoate 30 EC 2 ml/lit or Methyl demeton 25 EC 2 ml/lit.\n\n\n<b>Powdery mildew</b>\n\nDust Sulphur at 25 kg/ha or foliar spray with wettable sulphur 2 g/lit at the time of appearance of disease.\n\n\n<b>Harvest</b>\n\nThe crop matures in 7 to 8 months. Harvest the umbels 4 to 5 times at 10 to 15 days intervals, dry in sun for 4 to 5 days and seeds are threshed.\n\n\n<b>Yield</b>\n\nAbout 500 to 750 kg/ha/year can be obtained.</string>
    <string name="Allspice_info"><b>Soil and Climate</b>\n\nDeep rich loams with high humus content and lateritic soils are best suited\nAltitude : 1000 m above mean sea level.\nAnnual rainfall : 100to200 cm\nIdeal temperature : 270C\n\n\n\n<b>Propagation</b>\n\n<b>Seeds</b>Seeds are collected from high yielding and regular bearing trees. Seeds are extracted after soaking the fruits overnight in water and rubbing them in a sieve and washing with clean water. The seeds are ready for sowing after drying them in shade.Nursery beds of 1.2 m width are prepared with light soil incorporated with organic matter or a mixture of sand and coir dust or coir dust alone. After sowing the beds are mulched to hasten germination. Dried leaves, paper and damp sacks are used as mulches. Germination takes place 15 days after sowing.\n\n\n<b>Vegetative propagation</b>\n\nAir layering in the month of January.\n\n\n<b>Planting</b>\n\n9to10 months old seedlings of 25to30 cm height are used for field planting.\n\n\n<b>Spacing</b>\n\n6 m x 6 m. Since the plant is dioecious in nature, it is desirable to keep a male: female ratio of 1:10 in plantation.\n\n\n<b>Fertilizer</b>\n\nFYM (10 Kg) + 20:180:50 g of NPK per tree in the first year.\nFor grown up trees of 15 years or more, FYM (50 kg) + 300:250:750 g of NPK / tree is applied as two split doses. Apply manures in shallow trenches dug around the plant 1to1.5 m away from the tree.\n\n\n<b>Harvesting</b>\n\nClonally propagated plants start flowering in three years while the seed propagated plants in 6 years.Soil application of Paclobutrazol (1.25g/tree) induces flowering, increased number of panicles, flowers and setting of berries which in turn resulted in higher yield.Fully developed green berries are harvested.\n\n\n<b>Yield</b>\n\n20 to 25 kg dry berries per year/ tree.</string>

    <string name="Rose_info"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nGladiator, Baby Pink, Sofia Lawrence, YCD 1, YCD 2, YCD 3 are commonly cultivated.\n\n\n<b>2.Soil and climate</b>\n\nIt is generally suitable for higher elevation (1500 m and above). It can also be grown in the plains under ideal condition of fertile loamy soils with salt-free irrigation water. The ideal climate for rose growing should have temperature with a minimum of 15°C and maximum of 28°C. Light is important factor which decides the growth. The growth is slowed by day length, i.e. > 12 hours and heavy overcast, cloudy/mist conditions. High relative humidity exposes the plant to serious fungal diseases. In tropics the ideal temperature is 25°C – 30°C on sunny day and on cloudy day 18°C – 20°C. The optimum temperature should be 15°C – 18°C. These temperatures are extremely difficult to find and it’s therefore to compromise.\n\n\n<b>3.Propagation and planting</b>\n\nThe crop can be propagated by rooted cuttings or by budding on Briar root stocks in hills and on Edward Rose and Rosa indica in plains. One year old budded plants are planted in July - August at 75 cm x 75 cm spacing.\n\n\n<b>4.Planting of Rose</b>\n\nThe plants should be watered daily until they establish and thereafter once in a week. Pruning is done during March and October. Spray Diuran 2.5 kg a.i/ha to control weeds.  Avoid spray fluid coming in contact with Rose plants.\n\n\n<b>5.Support of the plants</b>\n\nPost is placed at internals of 3m on both sides of the bed. Along the sides of the bed, galvanized wires or plastic string are fastened at the posts at 30cm – 40cm intervals to support the plant. Between the wires across the bed, thin strings can be tied to keep the width of the beds constant.\n\n\n<b>6.Disbudding</b>\n\nVarieties produce some side buds below the center bud. These side buds have to be removed or disbudded. The disbudding must be done regularly and also as soon as possible in order to avoid . wounds in the upper leaf axil.\n\n\n<b>7.Dead shoot removal</b>\n\nIn the old plants the dead shoot or dried shoots on plants will serve as the host for fungi. So regularly these have to be removed.\n\n\n<b>8.Soil loosening on beds</b>\n\nAfter 6 months or so, there is every chance that the soil become stony and it has to be loosened for efficient irrigation.\n\n\n<b>9.Bending</b>\n\nLeaf is a source of food for every plant. There should be balance between Source (Assimilation) and sink (Dissimilation). After planting, 2 to 3 eye buds will sprout on main branch. These sprouts will grow as branches and these branches in turn form buds. The mother shoot is bend on 2nd leaf or nearer to the crown region. The first bottom break or ground shoot will start coming from the base. These ground shoots form the basic framework for production and thereon the ground shoots should be cut at 5th five pair of leaves and medium ground shoots should be cut at 2nd or 3rd five pair of leaves.\n\n\n<b>10.Defoliation</b>\n\nThe removal of leaves is known as defoliation. It is done mainly to induce certain plant species to flower or to reduce transpiration loss during periods of stress. Defoliation may be done by removal of leaves manually or by withholding water. The shoots are defoliated after pruning.\n\n\n<b>11.Manuring</b>\n\nAt three months interval, apply FYM at 10 kg and 8:8:16 g NPK per plant after each pruning. For cv. Happiness NPK may be applied at 75:150:50 g per plant per year.\n\n\n<b>12.Harvest</b>\n\nHarvesting is done with sharp secateure at the tight bud stage when the colour is fully developed and the petals have not yet started unfolding. There should be 1 to 2 mature leaves (those with five leaflets) left on the plant after the flower has been cut. The reason for leaving these matures leaves is to encourage production of new strong shoots. Harvesting is done preferably during early morning hours.\n\n\n<b>13.Limp necks</b>\n\nThe area of the stem just below the flower “wilts” and will not support the head. This may be due to insufficient water absorption; cutting off the lower 1 to 2 inches of stem and placing the cut stem in water at 37°C will revive the flower.\n\n\n<b>14.Blackening of rose petals</b>\n\nThis is caused by low temperature and high anthocyanin content. GA3 treatment causes accumulation of anthocyanin in petals of Baccara roses. This effect was more pronounced at low temperature (20°C at day and 4°C at night) than in higher temperature (30°C at day and 20°C at night).\n\n\n<b>15.Nutritional disorders</b>\n\nIron deficiencies can cause pale foliage. Adjusting the pH of the soil may solve this problem.\n\n\n<b>16.Yield</b>\n\nThe Hybrid Teas roses can yield about 70 – 80 stems per plant per year, while the Floribundas yield yields 80 -90 stems/plant/year.
</string>

    <string name="Chrysanthemum_info"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nStandard types: \nBonfire Orange, Bonfire Yellow.\nSpray types: \nReagan Yellow, Reagan White, Nanako, etc.\n\n\n<b>2.Climate: </b>\n\n<p> Cut chrysanthemums are grown under polyhouses with the following environmental conditions.
Temperature              : 16 - 250C\nRelative humidity        : 70 to 85 %\nCO2                          : 600 to 900 ppm\nPhotoperiod                : Long day conditions with 13 hours light and 11 hours darkness during vegetative stage Up to 4 to 5 weeks from planting and short day conditions with 10 hours light and 14 hours darkness during flower bud  initiation stage.</p>\n\n\n<b>3.Soil:</b> Well drained sandy loam soil with good texture and aeration or growing medium made of 1: 1: 2 of soil, compost and cocopeat with pH of 5.5 to 6.5.\n\n\n<b>4.Growing media</b>\n\nThe growing media consists of soil, compost and coco peat in the ratio of 1:1:2. The beds are formed with 1 m width, 0.3m height and at convenient length. The soil pH must be 6.5 with 1 to 1.5 EC (Electrical Conductivity).\n\n\n<b>5.Propagation: </b>\n\nTerminal cuttings and tissue culture plants are used. Terminal cuttings are widely used for commercial cultivation. Cuttings of 5 to 7 cm length are taken from healthy stock plants and are induced to root by treating with IBA (1000 ppm).\n\n\n<b>6.Planting: </b>\n\nBeds of 1m width, 0.3m height and convenient length are formed. Nets (with cell size depending on the spacing adopted) are placed on the beds and planting is done.\n\n\n<b>7.Spacing: </b>\n\n15x 15 cm (45 plants/m2) or 10 x 15 cm (67 plants/m2).\n\n\n<b>8.Irrigation: </b>\n\nDrip irrigation with 8 to 9 litres of water per m2 per day.\n\n\n<b>9.Nutrition: </b>\n\nBasal application of DAP - 50 g/m2Weekly schedule - from 3rd week after planting.\n\n\n<b>10.Growth regulators: </b>\n\nSpray GA3 (50 ppm) at 30, 45 and 60 days after planting to increase flower stem length.\n\n\n<b>11.Weed management: </b>\n\nWeeding and hoeing are done manually as and when required.\n\n\n<b>12.Plant protection</b>\n\nPests\n<b>Leaf miner:</b>\nSpray Imidacloprid @ 0.5 ml/l or Acetamiprid @ 0.3 g/l.\n<b>Thrips: </b>\nSpray Fipronil @ 1.0 ml/l. Keep Yellow Sticky Trap 10 nos. for 100 sq.m area.\n<b>Aphids: </b>\nSpray Methyl demeton @ 2 ml/l or Monocrotophos @ 1 ml/l.<b>Red spider mite: </b>\nSpray Abamectin 1.9 EC @ 0.5 ml/l or Propargite @ 2 ml/l.\n\n\n\n<b>13.Diseases</b>\n\nWhite Rust:\nSpray Azoxystrobin @ 1ml/l or Triflooxystrobin + Tebuconazole @   0.75 g/l.\nLeaf spot:\nSpray Macozeb @ 2g/l or Azoxystrobin @ 2 ml/l or Difenoconazole @ 0.5ml/l.\nWilt:\nSoil drenching with Carbendazim @ 1 g/l or Triflooxystrobin + Tebuconazole @ 0.75 g/l.\nPowdery mildew:\nSpray Wettable Sulphur @ 2g/l or Azoxystrobin @ 1ml/l.\n\n\n\n<b>14.Harvest</b>\n\nStandard types - Flowers are harvested when 2 - 3 rows of rays florets are perpendicular to the flower stalk.Spray types - When 50% flowers have shown colour for distant markets; when two flowers have opened and others have shown colour for local markets.
</string>

    <string name="Nutmeg_info"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nStandard types: \nBonfire Orange, Bonfire Yellow.\nSpray types: \nReagan Yellow, Reagan White, Nanako, etc.\n\n\n<b>2.Climate: </b>\n\n Cut chrysanthemums are grown under polyhouses with the following environmental conditions.Temperature : 16 to 250C\nRelative humidity : 70 to 85 %\nCO2  : 600 to 900 ppm\nPhotoperiod  : Long day conditions with 13 hours light and 11 hours darkness during vegetative stage (up to 4to5 weeks from planting) and short day conditions with 10 hours light and 14 hours darkness during flower bud  initiation stage.\n\n\n<b>3.Soil:</b> Well drained sandy loam soil with good te intoture and aeration or growing medium made of 1: 1: 2 of soil, compost and cocopeat with pH of 5.5 to 6.5.\n\n\n<b>4.Growing media</b>\n\nThe growing media consists of soil, compost and coco peat in the ratio of 1:1:2. The beds are formed with 1 m width, 0.3m height and at convenient length. The soil pH must be 6.5 with 1 to 1.5 EC (Electrical Conductivity).\n\n\n<b>5.Propagation: </b>\n\nTerminal cuttings and tissue culture plants are used. Terminal cuttings are widely used for commercial cultivation. Cuttings of 5to7 cm length are taken from healthy stock plants and are induced to root by treating with IBA (1000 ppm).\n\n\n<b>6.Planting: </b>\n\nBeds of 1m width, 0.3m height and convenient length are formed. Nets (with cell size depending on the spacing adopted) are placed on the beds and planting is done.\n\n\n<b>7.Spacing: </b>\n\n15 into 15 cm (45 plantsperm2) or 10  into 15 cm (67 plantsperm2).\n\n\n<b>8.Irrigation: </b>\n\nDrip irrigation with 8to9 litres of waterperm2perday.\n\n\n<b>9.Nutrition: </b>\n\nBasal application of DAP to 50 gperm2Weekly schedule to from 3rd week after planting.\n\n\n<b>10.Growth regulators: </b>\n\nSpray GA3 (50 ppm) at 30, 45 and 60 days after planting to increase flower stem length.\n\n\n<b>11.Weed management: </b>\n\nWeeding and hoeing are done manually as and when required.\n\n\n<b>12.Plant protection</b>\n\nPests\n<b>Leaf miner:</b>\nSpray Imidacloprid at 0.5 mlperl or Acetamiprid at 0.3 gperl.\n<b>Thrips: </b>\nSpray Fipronil at 1.0 mlperl. Keep Yellow Sticky Trap 10 nos. for 100 sq.m area.\n<b>Aphids: </b>\nSpray Methyl demeton at 2 mlperl or Monocrotophos at 1 mlperl.<b>Red spider mite: </b>\nSpray Abamectin 1.9 EC at 0.5 mlperl or Propargite atmlperl.\n\n\n\n<b>13.Diseases</b>\n\nWhite Rust:\nSpray Azo intoystrobin at 1mlperl or Trifloo intoystrobin + Tebuconazole at   0.75 gperl.\nLeaf spot:\nSpray Macozeb at 2gperl or Azo intoystrobin at 2 mlperl or Difenoconazole at 0.5mlperl.\nWilt:\nSoil drenching with Carbendazim at 1 gperl or Trifloo intoystrobin + Tebuconazole at 0.75 gperl.\nPowdery mildew:\nSpray Wettable Sulphur at 2gperl or Azo intoystrobin at 1mlperl.\n\n\n\n<b>14.Harvest</b>\n\nStandard types to Flowers are harvested when 2 to 3 rows of rays florets are perpendicular to the flower stalk.Spray types to When 50% flowers have shown colour for distant markets; when two flowers have opened and others have shown colour for local markets.</string>
    V
    <string name="Lilium"><b>1.Climate: </b>\n\nLiliums are best grown in green houses. Day temperature of 18to22°C and night temperature of 10to15°C are ideal.\n\n\n<b>2.Soil: </b>\n\nWell drained sterile medium (preferably leaf mould, cocopeat and FYM in equal parts) with pH 5.5 to 6.5 is ideal. Fumigate the beds with Dazomet at 30gperm2.\n\n\n<b>3.Propagation: </b>\n\n Liliums are commercially propagated through bulbs. A si into week cold storage period at 2oC to 5oC is needed to break dormancy. Bulbs can be stored at to 20C up to one year.\n\n\n<b>4.Spacing: </b>\n\n 20  into 15 cm, 15  into 15 cm or 15  into 10 cm (plant density varies between 30 and 60perm2 depending on cultivar and bulb size)\n\n\n<b>5.Irrigation: </b>\n\n6to 8 litresperm2perday during summer and 5 to 6 litresperm2perday during winter</string>

    <string name="goldenrod_info"><b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nBallardi, Golden Gate, Golden Wing, Monte D’ oro, Monte Solo, Peter Pan,Straehlen Krone, Super and Tara Gold.\n\n\n<b>2.Soil and climate</b>\n\nSandy loam and red loam soils with proper drainage are more suitable. It can be grown under varied climatic condition while the cooler climate gives high quality cut flower.\n\n\n<b>3.Season</b>\n\nThe crop can be cultivated throughout the    year\n\n\n<b>4.Propagation and Planting</b>\n\nPropagation is achieved through division of clusters or suckers. Soil is ploughed to fine tilth and flat beds are formed. The slips are then planted at 45  into 45 cm spacing.\n\n\n<b>5.Irrigation</b>\n\nIrrigation is done normally once in three days to keep the soil always wet and to induce profuse stalk production\n\n\n<b>6.Manuring</b>\n\nNPK at the rate of 140 : 175 : 150 kgperha. + 5 t FYMperha is applied as basal and half of the dose is applied after every harvest.\n\n\n<b>7.Aftercultivation </b>\n\nHand weeding is done as and when required.\n\n\n<b>8.Plant protection </b>\n\nPests\nLace bugs: \nSpray Malathion at 1 mlperl.\n\n\n<b>9.Diseases</b>\n\nPowdery mildew:\nSpray Wettable Sulphur 2gperl or Azo intoystrobin at 1mperl.\n\n\n<b>10.Leaf Spot: </b>\n\nSpray Copper O intoychloride 3gperl or He intoaconazole at1mlperlor Mancozeb at 2gperl.\n\n\n<b>11.Root rot:</b>\n\n  Soil drenching with Carbendazim at 1gperl.\n\n\n<b>Harvesting : </b>\n\nFirst harvest                    :  75 days after planting.\nHarvesting stage             :  When 25 % of the flowers have opened.\nCrop duration                  : 2 years.\n\n\n<b>12.Season of flowering and Harvesting</b>\n\nFirst harvest is made after 75th day of planting and continued daily for 30 days. This practice is repeated continuously for 2 years.\n\n\n<b>13.Yield</b>\n\nAn average yield of 3 lakhs stemspercropperha can be obtained.\n\n\n<b>14.Varieties</b>\n\nBallardi, Golden Gate, Golden Wing, Monte D’ oro, Monte Solo, Peter Pan, Straehlen Krone, Super and Tara Gold.\n\n\n<b>15.Soil andclimate </b>\n\nSandy loam and red loam soils with proper drainage are more suitable. It can be grown under varied climatic condition while the cooler climate gives high quality cut flower.\n\n\n<b>16.Yield</b>\n\nAn average yield of 3 lakhs stemspercropperha can be obtained</string>

    <string name="aster_info"> <b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nKamini, Poornima, Shashank, Violet Cushion, Phule Ganesh White, Phule Ganesh Pink, Phule Ganesh Violet, Phule Ganesh Purple.\n\n\n<b>2.Climate: </b>\n\n
Prefers cooler climates with day temperature of 20to300C, night temperature of 15to170C and relative humidity of 50to60%. Bright sunlight is required for growth and flowering.
\n\n\n<b>3.Soil: </b>\n\nOpen sunny locations with well drained red loamy soils with pH of 6.0 to 7.0\n\n\n<b>4.Propagation and planting: </b>\n\nPropagated through seeds; seed rate is 2.5 to 3.0 kgperha. 30to45 day old seedlings are transplanted in raised beds of 120  into 60  into 10 cm size.\n\n\n<b>5.Nutrition: </b>\n\nFYM at 10to15 tperha is applied during field preparation. NPK recommendation is 180:60:60 kgperha of which 90:60:60 kgperha is applied as basal and 90 kgperha of N is applied as top dressing 40 days after transplanting.\n\n\n<b>6.Land preparation and sowing</b>\n\nSoil is made into fine filth and flat beds are formed. Seeds are sown either by broad casting or line sowing at 20  into 15 cm.\n\n\n<b>7.Irrigation</b>\n\nIrrigation7.   is given once in 4to7 days according to soil moisture conditions.\n\n\n<b>8.Pinching: </b>\n\nPinching of growing tips is done 30 days after transplanting to induce lateral shoots.\n\\n<b>9.Manuring </b>\\Apply 5 t FYMperha along with NPK 70 : 175 : 75  kgperha as basal.\n\n\n<b>10.Weeding </b>\n\n    The crop needs two hand weedings.\n\n\n<b>11.Harvesting: </b>\n\nFor cut flower    : Flowers along with stalks or whole plants are harvestedFor loose flower: Individual flowers are harvested with short stems attached\n\n\n<b>12.Yield: </b>\n\n18 to 20 tperha.
</string>


    <string name="gerbera_info"><b>1.Climate: </b>\n\nProduction of quality flowers requires shade house (50%) or naturally ventilated polyhouse. Day temperature of 22to25°C and night temperature of 12to16°C are ideal\n\n\n<b>2.Soil: </b>\n\nWell drained, rich, light, neutral or slightly alkaline soil with pH range of 5.5 to 7.0.\n\n\n<b>3.Season  </b>\n\nThe crop can be cultivated throughout the year.\n\n\n<b>4.Propagation: </b>\n\n Commercially propagated through division of suckers and tissue culture plants.\n\n\n<b>5.Field preparation and planting: </b>\n\n Soil fumigation withFormaldehyde (100ml in 5lperm2) or Dazomet (30gperm2) is recommended to control soil borne pathogens (Phytophthora, Fusarium and Pythium). Raised beds of 1to2m width and 30cm height are prepared. Growing media consisting of FYM: sand: cocopeatperpaddy husk (2:1:1) is ideal.\n\n\n<b>6.Stem break</b>\n\nIt is a common post harvest disorder in cut gerberas. This is mainly caused by water imbalances. It could be ethylene controlled and associated with early senescence caused by water stress.\n\n\n<b>7.Yellowing and purple margin</b>\n\nNitrogen deficiency causes yellowing and early senescence of leaves. Phosphorus deficiency causes pale yellow colour with purple margin. Increase in levels of nitrogen and phosphorus were found to promote development of suckers and improve flowering in gerbera.\n\n\n<b>8.Bushiness:</b>\n\n An abnormality characterized by numerous leaves, short petioles and small laminae, which gives some cultivars of gerbera a bushy appearance known as bushiness. Nodes are not clearly distinguished and no internode elongation is seen.\n\n\n<b>9.</b>\n\n Based on stem length and diameter, flowers are graded in A, B, C and D.\n\n\n<b>10.Yield</b>\n\ The crop yields 2 stems per plant per month.  Harvest starts from 3rd month of planting and continued up to two years. Under open condition, 130 to160 flowers per m2 per year and under greenhouse condition, 175 to 200 flowers perm2per year can be obtained.</string>

    <string name="gladiolus_info"> \n\n\n<b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nTropic Sea, White Prosperity, Priscilla, Summer Sunshine, Pusa Swarnima, Jackson Ville Gold, KKL.1, Archana, Basant Bahar, Indrani, Kalima, Kohra, Aarti, Arka Kesar, Darshan, Dhiraj, Agnirekha, Archana, Bindiya, Shree Ganesh \n\n\n<b>2.Climate: </b>\n\n Subtropical and temperate climatic conditions are suitable. The crop performs well under a temperature range of 27 to 30°C. It requires full e intoposure to sunlight and performs well with long day conditions of 12 to 14 hour photoperiod.\n\n\n<b>3.Soil: </b>\n\n Well drained sandy loam soil rich in organic matter with pH of 6 to 7\n\n\n<b>4.Season </b>\n\nThis crop requires minimum 10 hours of sunlight to over come blindness. So season should be adjusted or light substitution should be given.\n\n\n<b>5.Propagation: </b>\n\nCommercial propagation is through corms. Cold storage of corms at 3 to 7°C for 3 months or treatment with Ethrel (1000ppm) or GA3 (100ppm) or Thiourea (500 ppm) is adopted for breaking corm dormancy\n\n\n<b>6.Field preparation and planting: </b>\n\nBeds of size 6  into 2 m are prepared and corms are planted at a depth of 5 cm adopting a spacing of 40  into 25 cm (88,888 plantsperha) or 25  into 25 cm (1,60,000 plantsperha7 \n\n\n<b>7.Planting season: </b>\n\nOctober for plains and MarchtoApril for hills.\n\n\n<b>8.Planting system</b>\n\nRidges and furrows system is adopted\n\n\n<b>9.Irrigation: </b>\n\n Irrigate at 7to10 day intervals in sandy soils and at less frequent intervals in heavy soils. Irrigation should be withheld at least 4to6 weeks before lifting of corms.\n\n\n<b>10.Nutrition: </b>\n\n 120 kg N, 150 kg P2O5 and 150 kg K2O per hectare is recommended, of which 60 kg N and entire dose of P2O5 and K2O is applied as basal dose. The remaining N is given in two split doses, 30 and 60 days after planting.\n\n\n<b>11.Aftercultivation</b>\n\nAfter the corms have sprouted well, watering should be done, if necessary. When the shoots are about 20 cm high they are covered by heaping the soil up to a height of 10 to 15 cm. This enables the plants to grow erect despite high winds and rains and suppresses weed growth. Earthing up the soil is a must in case of light soils. In case where spikes grow longer or stems are not strong enough to bear the lodging or mild stroke of wind, they are supported with about 1.5 meters strong stakes. Strings instead of stakes may be used at the time of the appearance of the spikes. Strings are stretched between the stakes along the row to provide easy and adequate support.\n\n\n<b>12.Harvesting of spikes: </b>\n\nGladiolus takes 110to120 days to produce spikes. While harvesting, at least four basal leaves should be retained on the plant to ensure proper development of corms and cormels.\n\n\n<b>13.Post harvest treatment and Grading</b>\n\n Soak the stem in water to avoid wilting and lodging of stem and flower.  Based on stem length and number of florets, the spikes are grouped into A, B, C, D grades.\n\n\n<b>14.Yield</b>\n\n2.0 to 2.5 lakh flower stalksperhapercrop</string>

    <string name="dendrobiumorchi_info"> \n\n\n<b>1.Climate</b>\n\n75% green shade net with 70 to 80% humidity, 18 to 28ºC temperature and light intensity of 1500to2000 foot candles is ideal for growing this tropical orchid.\n\n\n<b>2.Growing environment: </b>\n\n75% shade net house with 70to 80% humidity, day temperature of 21 to 29oC and night temperature of 18 to 21oC is ideal for growing this tropical orchid. In high rainfall zones, the shade net house should be provided with a rainshelter.\n\n\n<b>3.Propagation: </b>\n\nDivision of clumps, keikis, back bulbs and tissue culture plants.Containers and support : perforated earthen pots are ideal and the plants are staked with bamboo sticks.\n\n\n<b>4.Growing media: </b>\n\nMost common potting mi intoture consists of charcoal, broken pieces of bricks and tiles, coconut husk and fiber.\n\n\n<b>5.Irrigation: </b>\n\nMist or overhead sprinkler to provide water and to maintain humidity.\n\n\n<b>6.Nutrients: </b>\n\nFoliar application of NPK 20:10:10 at 0.2% at weekly intervals starting from 30 days after planting\n\n\n<b>7.Yield: </b>\n\n8 to 10 spikesperplantperyear\n\n\n<b>8.Pests: </b>\n\nSnail and Slug:Hand pick and destroy them immediately.</string>

    <string name="carnation_info"> <b>1.Growing environment: </b>\n\n Naturally ventilated aerodynamic steel frame structure.
    \n\n\n<b>2.Climate: </b>\n\nCool climate with day temperature of 18to240C and night temperature of 10to150C; relative humidity of 70 to75 %.\n\n\n<b>3.Soil: </b>\n\n
    Well drained red loamy soil with pH of 5.5 to 6.5.\n\n\n<b>4.Season</b>\n\nIt can be cultivated throughout the year as it is grown under controlled conditions.\n\n\n<b>5.Propagation and Planting</b>\n\nPlantletspersuckers can be used for planting. The terminal cuttings of 5to10 cm are treated with NAA at 500 ppm for 5 minutes to induce rooting. Cuttings are dipped in Carbendazim 2gperlit solution. Raised beds at 3 feet width and 45 cm height are formed at 45 cm interval and planting is done on top of the bed at 15  into 15 cm spacing. The cuttings normally develop good root system within 21 days.\n\n\n<b>6.Fumigation –</b>\n\n Dazomet at 30gperm2 or H2O2 at 300 mlperm2.
    \n\n\n<b>7.Bed size: </b>\n\n100 cm width, 30 cm height, convenient length with 40 cm foot path.\n\n\n<b>8.Spacing: </b>\n\n  6 row planting to 15 into15 cm (25 plantsperm2). 4 row planting to 15 into15cm (22 plantsperm2) .\n\n\n<b>9.Irrigation: </b>\n\n Drip system with drippers at 30 cm spacing (5to6 lperm2perday). \n\n\n<b>10.Growing condition</b>\n\n  Day temperature 20to25oC\n Nighttemperature 10to15oC\nCritical photoperiod 13 hours\nRH 50to60% \n\n\n\n<b>11.Disbudding</b>\n\nIn standard carnations, side buds should be removed whereas in spray carnations, the terminal bud has to be removed.\n\n\n<b>12.Irrigation</b>\n\nIrrigation is provided with drip system once in 2to3 days according to soil moisture to maintain water holding capacity at 60% to 65%. The optimum water requirement of the crop is 4to5 litperm2perday\n\n\n<b>13.Manuring</b>\n\nNeem cake 2.5 tonperha, Phosphorus 400 gper100 sq.feet and Magnesium sulphate 0.5 kgper100 sq.feet are applied as basal.
    \n\n\n<b>14.Top dressing</b>\n\nCalcium Ammonium Nitrate and MOP at 5:3 ratio is mi intoed and applied at 2.5 gperplantpermonth as top dressing\n\n\n<b>15.Yield: </b>\n\n15 flowersperplant (350 to 375 flowers stemsperm2) in 2 years period
</string>

    <string name="tuberose_info"> <b>1.Varieties</b>\n\nSingle –Calcutta Single, Me intoican Single, Phule Rajani, Prajwal, Rajat Rekha, Shringar, Khahikuchi Single, Hyderabad Single, Pune Single, Arka NirantraDouble –Calcutta Double, Hyderabad Double, Pearl Double, Swarna Rekha, Suvasini, Vaibhav.\n\n\n<b>2.Climate: </b>\n\n Tropical conditions with a temperature range of 28 to 300C \n\n\n<b>3.Soil</b>\n\n Well drained loamy soil having a pH of 6.5to7.5 is ideal for cultivation.\n\n\n<b>4.Propagation and planting</b>\n\nBulbs are used for commercial propagation. Bulbs (25 to 30 g) are planted (1,12,000 cormsperha) on the sides of ridges at 45  into 20 cm spacing at 2.5 cm depth during June to July. Bulbs are planted after 30 days of harvest. Dip the corms in 5000 ppm CCC (5 gperlit) before planting to increase the yield.\n\n\n<b>5.Manuring and after cultivation</b>\n\nManuring can be done with FYM 25 tperha and NPK 200:200:200 kgperha (IIHR Recommendation). Full P and K can be applied during the final preparation of plots, while N can be applied in 3 equal split doses i.e., at the final preparation of plot, 60 and 90 days after planting of bulbs.\n\n\n<b>6.Micronutrients: </b>\n\nFoliar spray ofZnSO4 0.5% + FeSO4 0.2% + Boric acid 0.1%.\n\n\n<b>7.Growth regulators: </b>\n\nFoliar application of GA3 at 50 to 100 ppm thrice at 40, 55 and 60 days after planting.\n\n\n<b>8.Plant protection</b>\n\nPests\nThrips: Spray Dimethoate at 1.5 mlperlit or Fipronil 5 % SC at 1.5 mlper l \nAphids \nSpary Dimethoate at 1.5 mlperlit or Imidacloprid at 1.5mlperl\nRoot knot nematode:\nApply Carbofuran 3 G 1 gperplant near the root zone and irrigate immediately to control nematode infestation.\n\n\n<b>9.Diseases</b>\n\nBasal rot (or) stem rot:\n Soil drenching with Carbendazim at 0.1 % \n\n\n<b>10.Crop duration</b>\n\nIt e intotends up to 2 years. The crop can be maintained for one more year with good management practices.\n\n\n<b>11.Harvest: </b>\n\nFor Loose flower and concrete e intotraction:\n Individual florets are plucked during early morning hours before 8 am daily, when they start to open.\nFor cut flower:\n Whole spike is cut leaving 4 to 6 cm from the base.\n\n\n<b>12.Yield: </b>\n\nLoose flowers: 14to15 tperha; Cut flower: 2 to 3 lakhs spikesperhaperyear; Bulbs and bulblets: 20 to25 tperha (at the end of 3rdyear).Concrete recovery: 0.08 to 0.11 %Flower yield ranges about 14to15 tperha. The concrete yield ranges about 8 to 10 kgperha.</string>


    <string name="oil_info"> <b>Introduction</b>\n\nOil palm (Elaeis guineensis Jacq.), is a native of West Africa and popularly known as African oil palm or red oil palm.It is known to be the highest edible oil yielding perennial crop. It produces two distinct oils, i.e., palm oil and palm kernel oil. Palm oil is derived from fleshy mesocarp of the fruit, which contains about 45 to 55% of oil. The palm kernel oil, obtained from the kernel of stony seed, is a potential source of lauric oil. Oil palm is the crop of the present and future vegetable oil economy of world as well as India.Palm oil has good consumer acceptance as cooking medium because of its price advantage. It is a good raw material for manufacturing oleo chemicals used in making soaps, candles, plasticizers etc. It has also a variety of uses, ranging from edible oil, cosmetics, pharmaceuticals to bio to fuel and bio to lubricant.\n\n\n<b>Distribution</b>\n\nIt is grown extensively in South to East Asian countries, (Malaysia, Indonesia and Papua New Guinea), African countries, (Nigeria, Ivory Coast, Ghana, Liberia, Sierra Leone, Cameroon, Republic of Congo and Zarie) and South American countries (Costa Rica, Panama, Columbia, British Guyana, Peru, Ecuador, Venezuela and Brazil). Malaysia, Indonesia and Nigeria are the leading producers of oil palm.Oil palm was introduced to India at National Royal Botanical Gardens, Kolkata during the year 1886. The Maharashtra Association for Cultivation of Sciences (MACS), Pune later introduced African dura palms along canal bunds, home gardens and, to some extent, in forest lands near Pune during 1947 to 1959. Large scale planting of oil palm was launched from 1971 to 1984 in Kerala by Plantation Corporation of Kerala Ltd. (subsequently taken over by Oil Pal India Ltd.) and Andaman Forest and Plantation Development Corporation Ltd., in Little Andaman Islands of Andaman and Nicobar Islands during 1976 to 1985.In the year 2020, the Reassessment Committee of ICAR to IIOPR has conducted a study to assess the potential area of Oil palm cultivation in the country including North to Eastern States and the Andaman and Nicobar Islands. As per the report of Reassessment Committee, a total 22 States have been identified with 27.99 lakh ha as having a potential area for Oil Palm cultivation in India.\n\n\n<b>Climatic requirements</b>\n\nOil palm is a humid crop. Requires evenly distributed rainfall of 150mmper month or 2500 to 4000mmperannum. Rainfall distribution in India is not even and adequate. Hence grow oil palm under assured irrigation conditions by adopting recommended practices. Crop comes up well between 29 to 33oC max. and 22 to 24oC min. temperatures and with bright sunlight for at least 5 hrs. per day. Humidity of more than 80% is required to come up well.\n\n\n<b>Soils</b>\n\nBest to suited soils are moist, well to drained, deep, loamy alluvial soils, rich in organic matter with good water permeability. At least one to meter depth of soil is required. Avoid highly alkaline, highly saline, waterlogged and coastal sandy soils.\n\n\n<b>Cultivated variety</b>\n\nTenera is the ruling hybrid and it is a cross between thick to shelled Dura and shell less Pisifera. Tenera has a thin shell, medium to high mesocarp content and high oil content.\n\n\n<b>Planting</b>\n\nBest season for planting is June to December i.e., during monsoon. In case of planting during summer, adequate irrigation, mulching and growing cover crops like sun hemp in the basin would help in avoiding hot winds during summer. 12  to 14 months old healthy seedlings with 1 to 1.3m height and 13 functional leaves are recommended for planting. While planting, 143 plants per hectare should be maintained with a spacing of 9m x 9m x 9m (triangular planting). Planting should be done in pit size of 60 cm x 60 cm x 60 cm (length, breadth and depth).Apply 250g Di Ammonium Phosphate or 400g Single Super Phosphate, 50g Phorate and mix with the soil at the base of the pit. Immediately after planting, form basin and give copious irrigation.\n\n\n<b>Irrigation management</b>\n\nOil palm requires sufficient irrigation, as it is a fast growing crop with high productivity and biomass production. Do not grow oil palm if assured and adequate irrigation facility is not available. For grown up yielding palms of 3 years age and above, a minimum of 150 to 200 liters of water per day is required. However, in older plantations during hot summer this quantity may be increased up to 300 lit.Basin method of irrigation is to be taken up when irrigation water is not a constraint. Required quantity of water is to be given at 4 to 5 days interval. Prepare irrigation channels in such a way that the individual palms are connected separately by sub to channel. For light soils, frequent irrigation with less water to be given. In heavy soils, irrigation interval can be longer.Drip or Microjet irrigation method is practiced. If land is of undulated terrain, drip or micro sprinkler irrigation can be advantageous. If drip irrigation is installed, four drippers are to be placed for each palm. If each dripper discharges 8 liters of water per hour, 5 hr. of irrigation per day is sufficient to discharge 160 litperday. In case of micro sprinklers (180o or 360o ) one each on either side of the palm can be installed. Drippersperjets should be periodically checked for proper discharge. Basins should be adequately mulched and covered with soil, which will help to conserve moisture.\n\n\n<b>Fertilizer management</b>\n\nOil palm is a gross feeder and demands a balanced and adequate supply of macro, secondary and micronutrients for growth and yield. It is advised to apply fertilizers at every three months interval.Fertilizer requirement of oil palm:Four equal split doses of fertilizers are to be applied starting from JuneperJuly at three month interval. For the newly planted crop, the first dose of fertilizer needs to be applied three months after planting. Add 50 to 100 kg FYM or 100kg green manure per palm along with the second dose of fertilizer application. Five kg neem cakeperpalm can also be applied. Broadcast the fertilizers around the clean to weeded basin, about 50 cm away from the palm base and incorporate into the soil with the help of fork. Irrigate the palms immediately after fertilizer application.To calculate fertilizer for a crop, click here.\n\n\n<b>Basin management</b>\n\nDuring first year, basins of 1 to m radius, second year 2 to  m radius, and the third year 3 to  m radius are to be taken around the palm by removing; the soil from inside so that the soil will not accumulate at the collar region. Basin area of oil palm represents its active root zone. Hence it must be kept clean and weed free to avoid competition for nutrients and water.\n\n\n<b>Weeding</b>\n\nTake up regular weeding manually or with the use of only recommended herbicides. Use preferably contact herbicides. Glyphosate (750mlperhaper year or 17.5 mlperbasin) is recommended for effective weed control. Herbicide mixtures of Paraquat with Atrazine, Monuron and Diuron sprayed on ground, twice a year can control the weeds, effectively.\n\n\n<b>Inter to cropping</b>\n\nOil palm is a wide spaced perennial crop with a long juvenile period of 3 years. Inter and intra row space can be used to generate income during the juvenile phase of the crop. Inter crop selected should be compatible with the main crop and should not compete with oil palm for light, water and nutrients. Any remunerative crop can be grown, but the most suitable crops are vegetables, banana, flowers, tobacco, chillies, turmeric, ginger, pineapple etc. While growing inter crops in mature oil palm gardens of 8 to  12 years age or palms attained a height of 3 meters, intercrops should be able to grow under partially shaded conditions and should not compete with oil palm for water, sunlight and nutrients (eg. cocoa, pepper, heliconia and ginger lilly).Do not cut the oil palm fronds. Do not tie oil palm fronds close to the stem for inter to cropping, which will reduce photosynthetic activity. Do not plough close to the palm base, which will cut the absorbing roots and thereby reduce intake of water and nutrients. Maximum number of green leaves should be retained on the palm.\n\n\n<b>Flowering</b>\n\nOil palm comes to flowering 14 to 18 months after planting. It produces both male and female flowers separately on the same palm. Male and female phases do occur naturally in consequent cycles in a palm.\n\n\n<b>Ablation</b>\n\nAblation is the removal of male and female flowersproduced in the early stages of plantation. This enables the plant to gain adequate stem girth, vigour and develop adequate root system. Flowering starts from 14th to 18th month after planting. Start ablation immediately after the appearance of inflorescences on the palms. They can be removed easily by hand pulling or using the tool developed at ICAR to Indian Institute of Oil Palm Research. Ablation can be extended up to 2 to 1per2 to 3 years depending upon the plant growth and vigour.\n\n\n<b>Pollination</b>\n\nOil palm is a highly cross to pollinated crop. Wind and insects assist pollination, but wind pollination is not adequate. Effective pollinating insects like Elaeidobius kamerunicus helps in good pollination and fruit set. Release of this weevil after 2 to 1per2 year of planting is advisable. If the plants are not having good girth and vigour, release the weevils after 3 years.\n\n\n<b>Mulching</b>\n\nMulching of oil palm basins is essential to conserve moisture as well as to control weeds. Mulching can be done with dried leaves, male flowers, coconut husk, empty bunches etc.\n\n\n<b>Harvesting</b>\n\nWhile harvesting a stalk length of 5 cm alone should be left. Harvesting should be done at 10 to 12 days interval. During rainy season, harvesting should be done at closer interval of 6 to 7 days as ripening is hastened after hot summer. In young plantations, we get more bunches with less bunch weight and in adult plantations the bunch weight is more but the bunch number is less.
\n\n\n<b>Yield</b>\n\nAt yield stabilizing period (4 to 8 years) : 12tperhaAt yield stabilized period (>8 years) : 20tperh
</string>

    <string name="coffee_info"> \n\n\n<b>Introduction</b>\n\nCoffee, native of Ethiopia, was introduced into India sometime during 1600 AD by a Muslim pilgrim, BabaBudan on the hills near Chikmangalur. Now coffee cultivation is mainly confined to the State of Karnataka, Kerala, Tamilnadu and Andhra Pradesh and on a limited scale to Arunanchal Pradesh, Assam, Madhya Pradesh, Manipur, Meghalaya, Mizoram, Nagaland, Orissa, Sikkim, Tripura and West Bengal.Coffee belongs to the family Rubiaceae. Though the genus Coffee consists of about 70 species, only three species are of economic importance. They are (i) C. arabica (Arabica coffee) (ii) C. cenephora (Robusta coffee) and (iii) C. Liberia (Tree coffee). The first two species are extensively cultivated.\n\n\n<b>Climate andsoil</b>\n\nClimatological factor like rainfall, temperature, elevation and aspect can influence economic production of coffee much more than soil factors. Soil should be deep, well drained, slightly acidic in reaction and rich in organic matter content. The optimum soil and climatic requirements for arabica and robusta under south India conditions are as follows\n\n\n<b>Nursery management</b>\n\nHealthy and mature fruits of normal size and appearance, three quarters to fully ripe are harvested from specially selected and marketed coffee plants for use as seed bearers. Floats are discarded, the sound fruits are pulped, the beans drained and sieved to remove defective beans. The beans are then mixed with sieved wood to ash, evenly spread out to a thickness of about 5cm and allowed to dry to facilitate uniform drying. Excess ash is rubbed to off after five days of drying. Germination beds, raised to a height of about 15 cm, one metre width and of convenient length are prepared. Four baskets of fully mature cattle manure or compost, about 2 kg. of finely sieved agricultural lime and 400g of rock phosphate are incorporated in a bed measuring 1m x 6m.\n\n\n<b>Sowing</b>\n\nSeeds should be sown with the flat side facing the soil at a distance of 1.5 – 2.5cm from one another in regular rows. A thin layer of fine soil is then spread. The bed is covered with a layer of about 5cm of paddy straw. The beds are watered daily and protected from direct sunlight by an overhead pandal. The seeds germinate in about 45 days. The seedlings are then transplanted to secondary nursery beds or raising polybag plants.\n\n\n<b>Transplanting in bags</b>\n\nCoffee seedlings are transplanted to polythene bags of 23 cm x 5 cm with 150 gauge thick in February or March when they are at the button or topee stage. The bags are filled with a prepared mixture of 6 parts of jungle soil, 2 parts of well rotten sieved cattle manure and 1 part of fine sand. At the time of transplanting it is preferable to slightly nip the tap root of the seedling. Transplanting is done preferably in the early morning hours or late in the afternoon.Regular watering and after to care of the seedlings should follow. Seedlings may be manured once in 2 months with urea dissolved in water, 20g. urea in 4.5 liters of water is sufficient for an area of 1 square metre. Adequate protection is given against nursery diseases and pests. Overhead shade in the nursery has to be thinned and finally removed after the onset of monsoon.\n\n\n<b>Preparation of land</b>\n\nClean felling is not advocated. Selective retention of desired species of wild shade trees is essential. The land should be divided into blocks of convenient size with foot path and roads laid out in to between. In steapy area, terracing and contour planting may also be adopted.Spacing for arabica and robusta coffee is 2 to 2.5m and 2.5 to 4m respectively on either way. A close planting at 1 to 1.5 m eitherway and reduce the population by half after one or two harvests is good. Pits of 45 cm, are usually opened after the first few summer shower and seedlings of 16 to 18 months old are planted during June or September – October. A hole is made in the center of the pit after leveling the soil. The seedling is placed in the hole with its tap root and lateral roots spread out in proper position. The hole is then filled. The soil around the seedlings is packed firmly and evenly in such a way that 3cm high above the ground to prevent stagnation of water around the collar. The seedlings are provided with cross stakes to prevent wind damage.\n\n\n<b>Training and Pruning</b>\n\nTraining of the bush is necessary to have a strong frame work which promotes producing of bearing wood. Coffee is trained in two systems viz.1. Single stem system: When the plant reaches a height of 75 cm in Arabica or 110 to 120 cm in robusta, lit is topped. This helps to restrict vertical growth, facilitate lateral spreading and increase the bearing area. In this system, a second tier is also allowed sometimes depending upon the soil fertility and plant’s vigour.Multiple stem system – It is common in Kenya, Tanzania, but not practiced in India.Pruning in coffee is generally done immediately after harvest and till the onset of monsoon. It is essentially a thinning process and is done mainly to divert the vigour of the plants to certain parts by pruning the other parts. Pruning involves (a) centering to removal of the vegetative growth up to 15 cm redius from the centre and up to the first node of all primary branches (b) desuckering – removal of small sprouts arising from the axis of the leaves which otherwise grow towards the inner side and cause shade and become unproductive wood and (d) nipping to growing tip of primary branches is removed to encourage secondaries and tertiaries.\n\n\n<b>Soil management</b>\n\nSoil management practices aim at conserving soil and water and in general to make the soil perform its functions satisfactorily. It includes the following practices in coffee.a. Digging : In the new clearing, the field is given a thorough digging to a depth of about 35 to 45 cm towards the end of the monsoon. All weeds and vegetative debris are completely turned under and buried in the soil while the stumps are removed. Once the coffee plants have closed in, annual digging is not done.b. Scuffing or soil stirring : In established coffee fields, scuffling or soil stirring is done towards the beginning of the dry period. It controls weeds and also conserves soil moisture.c. Trenching : Trenches and pits are dug or renovated in a staggered manner between rows of coffee along the contour during August to October when the soil is fairly easy to work. These are 50 cm wide and 25cm deep and can be of any convenient length.d. Mulching : Mulching young coffee clearings helps to maintain optimum soil temperature and conserve soil moisture and acts as an effective erosion control measure. Mulching also adds to fertility of the soil.e. Weed control: New clearings are hand to weeded three to four times a year and established coffee two to three times. During the monsoon, the weeds are slashed back. Another weeding is done towards the end of the monsoon. Clean weeding is generally done during the post to monsoon period. Chemical weedicides have gained popularly in larger plantations. Gramoxone at 1.25 litres in 450 litres of water per hectare has been found to be the best. This should follow slash weeded plots after 10 to 15 days.f. Irrigation: Sprinkler irrigation is mainly used as an insurance against failure of good blossom or backing showers. It is also used on young plantations, marginal areas where water is available in plenty to help in establishment of coffee and shade.g. Soil acidity and liming: The heavy rainfall in coffee growing zones of South India brings about leaching in calcium and magnesium leading to soil acidity. Besides, continuous use of acid forming fertilizers like ammonium sulphate also make the soil acidic. As the ill effects of soil acidity are more, periodical lime application is essential to correct the soil pH for good productivity. The quantity of lime to be applied is based on soil pH and lime requirement. Agricultural lime and dolomitic lime are the most commonly used liming materials. It can be applied to the soil at any time during the year provided there is a gap of one month or a few showers between lime and fertilizer applications. It is also desirable to apply lime when there is sufficient moisture in the soil for quick response.\n\n\n<b>Shade management</b>\n\nUnder the climatic conditions existing in India, Coffee is being cultivated under shade. It comprises of two canopies to lower or temporary and upper or permanent. High light intensities and temperature prevailing during the drought period are not conducive for normal and healthy growth of coffee plants. Therefore, there is necessity for protecting the coffee plants during the above period by providing both temporary (lower) and permanent (upper) shade trees.Dadap (Erythrina lithosperma) is used as a lower canopy shade in India. It is planted along with coffee in new clearings. When stakes are planted in June, they grow quickly using the moisture available in the soil. Next to dadap, silver oak (Grevillea robusta) is the most commonly used tree for temporary shade. The most popular permanent shade trees found in South India are Albizzia lebbek, A.moluccana, A.odoratissima, Artocarpus integrifoila, Cedrella toona, Dalbergia latifolia, Ficus glomerata, F.infectoria, F.retusa and Maesopsis eminii.Permanent shade trees are generally planted about 12 to 14 metres apart. It is advisable to plant a large number initially and thin out as the trees grow and spread out. The trees have to be regulated in such a way that in course of tome, they have their canopy about 10 to 14 metres above the coffee. Shade trees require constant attention by way of pruning and lopping to provide the required filtered shade to coffee. The most convenient time to regulate shade is after pruning and liming.\n\n\n<b>Manuring</b>\n\nCoffee plants produce every year fresh wood for the succeeding crop concomitant with thefunction of maturing the current betties. Hence, they require a regular supply of nutrients. Besides, being grown in heavy rainfall area, the losses of nutrients due to leaching and fixation are to be offset by regular application of adequate quantities of fertilizers. The peak periods of demands for nutrientsare at the time of flowering fruit to set and development and maturation of the crop. Based on all these factors, Coffee Board recommends the following dose of fertilizer for coffee</string>

    <string name="turmeric_info"> \n\n\n<b>Introduction</b>\n\nTurmeric is the dried rhizome of Curcuma longa, a herbaceous plant. The rhizome has 1.8 to 5.4% curcumin, the pigment and 2.5 to 7.2% of essential oil. It is used as an important condiment and as a dye with varied applications in drug and cosmetic industries. In India, Andhra Pradesh is the leading state followed by Maharashtra, Tamil Nadu, Orissa, Kerala and Bihar.\n\n\n<b>Requirement</b>\n\n<b>Climate</b>\n\nTurmeric can be grown from sea level to 1500m in the hills, at a temperature range of 20 to 300C with a rainfall of 1500 to 2250mm per annum. It is also grown as an irrigated crop.<b>Soil</b>\n\nIt thrives best in a well drained sandy or clayey loam rich in humus content. It can be grown on different soil viz. light black, ashy loam and red soils to clay loams.\n\n\n<b>Varieties</b>\n\nCO1, BSR.1, Suguna, Suvarna, Sudharshana, Krishna, Sugundham, Roma, Suroma, Rajendra Sonia, Ranga, Rasmi.\n\n\n<b>material and planting</b>\n\nThe areas where the rainfall is sufficiently early, crop can be planted during April to May with the receipt of pre to monsoon showers. Since turmeric is a shade loving plant, castor or Sesbania grandiflora may be raised along the border lines in the field. Well developed healthy and disease free whole or split mother rhizomes weighing 35 to 44g are used for planting. Rhizomes are treated with 0.3% Dithane M to 45 and 0.5% Malathion for 30 minutes before storing. Small pits are made with a hand hoe in the beds in rows with a spacing of 25x 30 cm and covered with soil or dry powdered cattle manure. The optimum spacing in furrows and ridges is about 45 to 60 cm between the rows and 25 cm between the plants. A seed rate of 2500kg of rhizomes are required for one hectare.\n\n\n<b>Fertilizers</b>\n\nFarm yard manure at10 tperha is applied as basal dressing. Beds are earthed up each time after top dressing. The NPK recommendation is 125:37:37kg per ha. Whole Phosphorus (P) and Potash (K2O) is given as basal dose at the time planting while Nitrogen (N) is applied as 25kg each at basal, 30,60,90 and 120 days after planting i.e., 125kg N.\n\n\n<b>Intercultural Operations</b>\n\nMulching and weedingThe crop is to be mulched immediately after planting with green leaves or banana psuedostem or sugarcane trash at the rate of 12 to 15 tonnes per hectare. It may be repeated for second time after 50 days with the same quantity of green leaves after weeding and application of fertilizers. Weeding may be done thrice at 60,120and 150 days after planting depending upon weed intensity.\n\n\n<b>Irrigation</b>\n\nDepending on the soil types, irrigated crops require 15 to 20 irrigations in heavy soils and 35 to 40 in light soils. Moisture stress affects the growth and development of the plant especially during the rhizome bulking stage.\n\n\n<b>Plant protection</b>\n\n<b>Pest</b>\n\nShoot borer (Conogethes punctiferalis)The presence of bore hole on the pseudostems through which the frass is extruded and the withered central shoot are the symptoms of pest infestation.\n\n\n<b>Control</b>\n\nSpray Malathion 0.1% at monthly interval from July to October. Rhizome scale (Aspidiotus hartii)They feed on the plant sap and in the field in severe cases plants wither and dry. In storage the pest infestation results in shrivelling of buds an rhizomes and may also affect the sprouting of rhizomes.\n\n\n<b>Control</b>\n\nDip the rhizomes in quinalphos 0.1% twice prior to storage and sowing.\n\n\n<b>Diseases</b>\n\nRhizome rot (Pythium graminicolum)Collar region of the pseudostems become soft and water soaked, and the plant collapses.\n\n\n<b>Control</b>\n\nDrench the soil with 0.3% Dithane M to 45. Dip rhizomes in the same chemical solution for 30 minutes before storage and at the time of sowing.Leaf blotch (Taphrina maculans)There are small, oval, rectangular or irregular brown spots on either side of the leaves. The leaves turn yellow.\n\n\n<b>Control</b>\n\nSpray 0.2% Dithane M.45.Nematodes (Meloidogyne sp., Radopholus similis)\n\n\n<b>Control</b>\n\nApply to soil aldicarb or carbofuran granules at 1kg a.iperha.\n\n\n<b>Harvesting</b>\n\nDepending upon the variety, the crop becomes ready for harvest in seven to nine months. The land is ploughed and the rhizomes are gathered by hand picking or the clumps are carefully lifted with a spade. Harvested rhizomes are cleaned of mud and other extraneous matter adhering to them. The average yield per hectare is 20 to 25 tonnes of green turmeric.Processing\n\n\n<b>Curing</b>\n\nThe fresh turmeric is cured before marketing. Curing involves boiling of fresh rhizomes in water and drying in the sun. The mother rhizomes and the fingers are generally cured separately In the traditional method, the cleaned rhizomes are boiled in copper or galvanized iron or earthen vessels, with water just enough to soak them. Boiling is stopped when froth comes out and white fumes appear giving out a typical odour. The boiling lasts for 45 to 60 minutes when the rhizomes are soft. In the improved scientific method of curing the cleaned fingers (approximately 50kg) are taken in a perforated trough of size 0.9 X 0.55x0.4m, made of GI or MS sheet with extended parallel handle. The perforated trough containing the lingers are then immersed in the pan. The alkaline solution (0.1% sodium carbonate or sodium bicarbonate) is poured into the trough to immerse the turmeric fingers. The whole mass is boiled till the fingers become soft. The cooked fingers are taken out of the pan by lifting the trough and draining the solution into the pan. The cooking of turmeric is to be done within two to three days after harvesting. The cooked fingers are dried in the sun by spreading 5 to 7 cm thick layers on bamboo mat or drying floor. During night time, the materials should be heaped or covered. Drying is completed in 10 to 15 days.\n\n\n<b>Polishing</b>\n\nThe appearance is improved by smoothening and polishing outer surface by manual or mechanical rubbing. The improved method is by using hand operated barrel or drum mounted on a central axis, the sides of which are made of expanded metal mesh. When the drum filled with turmeric is rotated at 30 rpm, polishing is effected by abrasion of the surface against the mesh as well as by mutual rubbing against each other as they roll inside the drum. The turmeric is also polished in power to operated drums. The yield of polished turmeric from the raw materials varies from 15 to 25%.\n\n\n<b>Colouring</b>\n\nIn order to impart attractive yellow colour, turmeric suspension in water is added to the polishing drum in the last 10 minutes. Composition of emulsion for colour coating of 100kg of half boiled turmeric is Alum 0.04kg, turmeric powder 2kg, castor seed oil 0.14kg, sodium bisulphate 30g, concentrated hydrochloric acid 30ml. When the rhizomes are uniformly coated with suspension, they may be dried in the sun.
</string>

    <string name="cardomon_info"> <b>Intruduction</b>\n\nCardamom ( Elettaria cardamomum L.) popularly, known as Queen of Spices is native to the evergreen rainy forests of Western Ghats in South India. It is cultivated in Kerala, Karnataka and Tamil Nadu. Cardamom is used for flavouring various preparations of food, confectionery, beverages andliquors.\n\n\n<b>Requirement</b>\n\n<b>Climate</b>\n\n
It is grown in the areas where the annual rainfall ranges from 1500 to 4000mm, with a temperature range of 10 to 35o C and an altitude of 600 to 1200m above Mean Sea Level. Rainfall distribution should be good and summer showers during February to April are essential for panicle initiation.\n\n\n<b>Soil</b>\n\nDeep black loam soil with high humus content found in the forest region is best suited for cultivation. It also grows on laterite soils, clay loams and rich black soils having good drainage. Sandy soil is not suitable.\n\n\n<b>Varieties</b>\n\nCoorg cardamom Malabar Selection to 1 (CCS to 1), ICRI to 1, ICRI to 2, Mudigree to 1, PV to 1, SKP to 14.\n\n\n<b>Nursery</b>\n\nCardamom is propagated mainly through seeds and also through suckers each consisting of atleast one old and a young aerial shoot. Seedlings are normally raised in primary and secondary nurseries. Raised beds are prepared after digging the land to a depth of 30 to 45cm. The beds of 1m width and convenient length raised to a height of about 30cm are prepared. A fine layer of humus to rich forest soil is spread over the beds. Seed are to be collected from well ripe capsules. Immediately after harvesting, the husk is removed and the seeds are washed repeatedly in water for removing the mucilaginous coating. Seeds should be sown immediately after extraction. One kg of seed capsules may produce 5000 seedlings. Sowing may be taken up during November to January and is done in rows. Seed beds are to be dusted with chloropicrin or Carbon disulphide. The germination commences in about 30 days and may continue for a month or two. After germination, the mulch is to be removed.\n\n\n<b>Manuring</b>\n\nManuring at the rate of 90g nitrogen (N), 60g phosphorus (P2O5) and 120g potash (K2O) per bed of 5x1m size, in three equal split doses at an interval of 45 days is recommended to produce healthier seedlings. The first dose of fertilizer may be applied 30 days after transplanting in the secondary nursery.\n\n\n<b>Land preparation</b>\n\nPits of 45x45x30cm size are dug in April to May and filled with a mixture of top soil and compost or well decomposed farm yard manure. In slopy land, contour terraces may be made and pits may be taken along the contour and a close planting (2mx1m) is advisable along the contour.\n\n\n<b>Planting</b>\n\nThe planting is carried out during the rainy season commencing from June. Seedlings are to be planted up to the collar region for better growth. Cloudy days with light drizzle are ideal for planting. Generally in Kerala and Tamil Nadu, the seedlings are transplanted in March to May at a spacing of 20x 20 cm and mulched immediately. Beds are to be covered with an over head pandal and should be watered regularly.\n\n\n<b>Fertilizer</b>\n\nA fertilizer does of 75kg nitrogen (N), 75kg phosphorus (P2O5) and 150g potash (K2O) per ha is recommended under irrigated condition for high yielding plantation yielding 100 kgperha and above and a dose of 30:60:30 kgperha is recommended for gardens under rainfed condition. Organic manures like compost or cattle manure may be given at5 kg per clump. Fertilizer is applied in two split doses. The first application during May will help in the production of suckers and development of capsules and the second application during late September will help the initiation of panicles and sucker. Only half the dose of fertilizer is to be applied during the first year and full dose is given from second year onwards. Application of fertilizer is done at a radius of 30cm and covered with a thin layer of soil.\n\n\n<b>Irrigation</b>\n\n In order to overcome the dry spell during summer, it is necessary to irrigate the crop to get maximum production as it helps in initiation of panicles, flowering and fruit set. They may be irrigated at an interval of 10 to 15days till the onset of monsoon.\n\n\n<b>Intercultural operations</b>\n\n<b>Mulching</b>\n\nIt is an important cultural practice in cardamom. Fallen leaves of the shade trees are utilized for mulching. Sufficient mulch should be applied during November to December to reduce the ill effects of drought, which prevails for nearly 4 to 5 months during summer. Exposing the panicle over mulch is beneficial for pollination.\n\n\n<b>Weeding</b>\n\nThe first round of weeding is to be carried in May to June, the second in August to September and the third in December to January. Weedicides like paraquat at625ml in 500 litres of water may be sprayed in the interspaces between rows leaving 60cm around the plant base.\n\n\n<b>Trashing</b>\n\nTrashing consists of removing old and drying shoots of the plant once in a year with the onset of monsoon under rainfed conditions and 2 to 3 times in high density plantations provided with irrigated facilities.\n\n\n<b>Shade</b>\n\n regulationIt is very sensitive to moisture stress. Shade helps to regulate soil moisture as well as temperature and provides congenial micro to climate for cardamom. Excess shade is also quite detrimental and shade has to be regulated so as to provide 50 to 60% filtered sunlight. In order to provide adequate light during monsoon, shade regulation may be taken up before the onset of monsoon.\n\n\n<b>Earthing</b>\n\n upAfter the monsoon is over, a thin layer of fresh fertile soil, rich in organic matter may be earthed up at the base of the clump, covering up to the collar region be scraping between the rows or collecting soil from staggered trenchespercheck pits. This encourages new growth.\n\n\n<b>Harvesting and processing</b>\n\nCardamom plants normally start bearing two years after planting. In most of the areas the peak period of harvest is during October to November. Picking is carried out at an interval of 15 to 25 days. Ripe capsules are harvested in order to get maximum green colour during curing. After harvest, capsules are dried either in fuel kiln or electrical drier or in the sun. It has been found that soaking the freshly harvested green cardamom capsules in 2% washing soda solution for 10 minutes prior to drying helps to retain the green colour during drying. When drier is used, it should be dried at 45 to 50o C for 14 to 18 hours, while for kiln, over night drying at 50 to 60 o C is required. The capsules kept for drying are spread thinly and stirred frequently to ensure uniform drying. The dried capsules are rubbed with hands or coir mat or wire mesh and winnowed to remove any foreign matter. They are then sorted out according to size and colour, and stored in black polythene lined gunny bags to retain the green colour during storage.
</string>


    <string name="belevine_info"><b>Varieties</b>\n\nKarpurakodi, Kallarkodi, Revesi, Karpuri, SGM 1, SGM (BV)  to  2, Vellaikodi, Pachaikodi, Sirugamani 1, Anthiyur kodi, Kanyur kodi and Bangla type are under cultivation\n\n\n<b>Soil and climate</b>\n\nWell drained fertile clay loams are suitable. It does not tolerate saline and alkaline conditions. Betelvine require a cool humid with considerable humidity and regular supply of moisture in the soil is essential.\n\n\n<b>Seeds and sowing</b>\n\nThe vines are propagated by terminal stem cutting or setts about 30  to  45 cm long. Setts obtained from the top portions of the vines are easy to root and hence best for planting. On an average 1, 00,000 setts are required for planting one hectare. Setts with vigorous apical buds and nodal adventitious roots are selected and planted at the base of the live supports, which are to be planted 4 to 5 months earlier.\n\n\n<b>Season</b>\n\nNovember  to  December and January – February are optimum for cultivation.\n\n\n<b>Preparation of field</b>\n\nThe field is prepared to a fine tilth and beds of 2 m wide are formed to a convenient length. Provide drainage trenches of 0.5 m width by 0.5 m depth in between two adjoining beds. Plant the seeds of the live supports i.e. Agathi (Sesbania grandiflora) in long rows. About 750 banana suckers are planted at the edges of the beds, which are used, for tying the vines on the live support and for packing the betel leaf.  When the Agathi plants reach 4 m height, they are topped off for maintaining the height. The crop is planted in two rows in beds of 180 cm width on Agathi plants with a spacing of 45 cm between plants in the row.\n\n\n<b>Irrigation</b>\n\nIrrigate the field immediately after planting and afterwards once in a week.\n\n\n<b>Aftercultivation</b>\n\nTraining of the live standards Before the establishment of vines, the side branches of Agathi trees up to a height of 2 m are removed for early creeping of the vines.\n\n\n<b>Training of the vines</b>\n\nTraining is done by fixing the vine at intervals of 15 to 20 cm along the standards loosely with the help of banana fibre. Training is done at every 15  to  20 days interval depending upon the growth of vines.\n\n\n<b>Lowering of vines</b>\n\nUnder normal cultivation, the vines grow to height of 3 m in one year period. When they reach this height their vigour to produce normal size leaf are reduced and they need rejuvenation by lowering during March  to  April. After the vine is lowered, the tillers spring up from the nodes at the bends of the coiled vines at the ground level and produce many primary vines. Irrigation should be given after each lowering.\n\n\n<b>Manuring</b>\n\nApply 150 kg Nperhaperyear through Neem cake (75 kg N) and Urea (75 kg N) and 100 kg P2O5 through Super phosphate and 30 kg Muriate of potash in three split doses first at 15 days after lifting the vines and second and third dose at 40  to  45 days intervals.  Apply on beds shade dried neem leaf or Calotropis leaves at 2 tperha and cover it with mud (2 t in 2 split doses).\n\n\n<b>Scale insects</b>\n\nSelect scale to free seed vines. Spray Chlorpyriphos 20 EC 2 mlperlit when one or two scales are noticed on the basal portion of the stemperleaves. Direct the spray solution to the basal portion of the vines.  Spray NSKE 5 % or Malathion 50 EC 1 mlperlit.\n\n\n<b>Mites (Sevvattai) </b>\n\nMites can be controlled by spraying Wettable sulphur 50 WP at 1 gperlit or Dicofol 18.5 EC 0.5 mlperlit.\n\n\n<b>Sooty mould (Aphids) </b>\n\n To control aphids spray Chlorpyriphos at 2 mlperlit on Agathi leaves. Clip off excess Agathi leaves.\n\n\n<b>Mealy bugs</b>\n\nMealy bugs can be controlled by spraying Chlorpyriphos 20 EC at 2 mlperlit or Dimethoate 30 EC 2mlperlit. Concentrate the spray towards the collar region.\n\n\n<b>Nematode</b>\n\nApplication of Neem cake at 1 tperha or shade dried Calotropis leaves at 2.5 tperha can be applied to soil for controlling the nematode populations.Soil application of Bacillus subtilis (BbV 57) or Pseudomonas fluorescens at 10 g per vine for the control of root knot nematode and quick wilt of betel vine \n\n\n<b>Bacterial leaf spot, blight and bacterial stem rot</b>\n\nSpray Streptocycline at 400 ppm + Bordeaux mixture at 0.25% at the time of first disease symptoms appear. Continue spraying at 20 days intervals.  Always spray the chemical after plucking the leaves.\n\n\n<b>Anthracnose (Theechal) </b>\n\n Spray 0.2 % Ziram or 0.5% Bordeaux mixture after plucking the leaves after the first appearance of the symptom. The variety Karpoori is susceptible to the disease. \n\n\n<b>Powdery mildew</b>\n\n Powdery mildew can be controlled by spraying 0.2% Wettable sulphur after plucking the leaves. \n\n\n<b>Harvest</b>\n\nIt depends upon the growth of the vines and market condition. Once harvesting starts it continues almost every day.\n\n\n<b>Yield</b>\n\nAbout 75 to 100 lakh leavesperhaperyear can be obtained
</string>

    <string name="gerenim_info"> <b>Varieties</b>\n\nAlgerian, Reunion, IIHR to 8, Kodaikanal 1 and Egyptian are the popular varieties under cultivation. \n\n\n<b>Soil and climate</b>\n\nA deep light porous well drained soil rich in organic matter and acidic in reaction with a pH 5.5 to 6.0 is suitable.  An elevation ranging from 1000  to  2400 m with an annual rainfall of 100 to 150 cm evenly distributed throughout the year is ideal.\n\n\n<b>Propagation</b>\n\nGeranium is propagated by stem cuttings. Cuttings of about 10 to 15 cm are taken from current season growth with a well formed crown of leaves with 3  to  4 nodes and terminal bud. Dipping basal portion of the cuttings in 200 ppm of IBA increase the rooting efficiency. Cuttings planted in raised nursery beds will be ready for planting with in 60 days.\n\n\n<b>Planting</b>\n\nThorough field preparation leading to fine tilth condition is essential.  Rooted cuttings of 2 months age are planted at a spacing of 45 x 45 cm during April  to  May.\n\n\n<b>Manuring</b>\n\nFYM 25 tperha and NPK 25:150:100 kgperha are applied as basal. Remaining 125 kg Nperha in 5 equal splits is applied at every 2 months interval. During June to July of every year, ZnSo4 20 kgperha and Boron 10 kgperha are applied.\n\n\n<b>Irrigation</b>\n\nGeranium is usually grown as a rainfed crop. Irrigation during dry periods increases the yield.\n\n\n<b>Aftercultivation</b>\n\nWeedings, uprooting and burning the diseased plants throughout the life cycle of the plant. From the second year onwards give a deep soil forking around the plants to improve the growth of more suckers.\n\n\n<b>Pruning</b>\n\nPruning of the bushes is necessary when the bush shows signs of decline.  The branches are cut back leaving 15  to  20 cm once in 4  to  5 years.\n\n\n<b>Harvest and distillation</b>\n\nIn the year of planting only one harvest can be done at 7  to  8 months and thereafter 3 or 4 harvests can be done in a year.  The tender tip portion with 6  to  12 nodes constitutes the materials for harvest. The harvested material is withered in shade for two to three hours and distilled.\n\n\n<b>Yield</b>\n\nHerbage                     :           20  to  25 tperha\nOil yield                     :           15  to  20 kgperha\n
</string>

    <string name="cinaman_info"> <b>Varieties</b>\n\nAlgerian, Reunion, IIHR to 8, Kodaikanal 1 and Egyptian are the popular varieties under cultivation. \n\n\n<b>Soil and climate</b>\n\nA deep light porous well drained soil rich in organic matter and acidic in reaction with a pH 5.5 to 6.0 is suitable.  An elevation ranging from 1000  to  2400 m with an annual rainfall of 100 to 150 cm evenly distributed throughout the year is ideal.\n\n\n<b>Propagation</b>\n\nGeranium is propagated by stem cuttings. Cuttings of about 10 to 15 cm are taken from current season growth with a well formed crown of leaves with 3  to  4 nodes and terminal bud. Dipping basal portion of the cuttings in 200 ppm of IBA increase the rooting efficiency. Cuttings planted in raised nursery beds will be ready for planting with in 60 days.\n\n\n<b>Planting</b>\n\nThorough field preparation leading to fine tilth condition is essential.  Rooted cuttings of 2 months age are planted at a spacing of 45 x 45 cm during April  to  May.\n\n\n<b>Manuring</b>\n\nFYM 25 tperha and NPK 25:150:100 kgperha are applied as basal. Remaining 125 kg Nperha in 5 equal splits is applied at every 2 months interval. During June to July of every year, ZnSo4 20 kgperha and Boron 10 kgperha are applied.\n\n\n<b>Irrigation</b>\n\nGeranium is usually grown as a rainfed crop. Irrigation during dry periods increases the yield.\n\n\n<b>Aftercultivation</b>\n\nWeedings, uprooting and burning the diseased plants throughout the life cycle of the plant. From the second year onwards give a deep soil forking around the plants to improve the growth of more suckers.\n\n\n<b>Pruning</b>\n\nPruning of the bushes is necessary when the bush shows signs of decline.  The branches are cut back leaving 15  to  20 cm once in 4  to  5 years.\n\n\n<b>Harvest and distillation</b>\n\nIn the year of planting only one harvest can be done at 7  to  8 months and thereafter 3 or 4 harvests can be done in a year.  The tender tip portion with 6  to  12 nodes constitutes the materials for harvest. The harvested material is withered in shade for two to three hours and distilled.\n\n\n<b>Yield</b>\n\nHerbage                     :           20  to  25 tperha\nOil yield                     :           15  to  20 kgperha\n
</string>

</resources>